[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome to episode 29. 90 of the ask
show. I hope you're all doing great.
Let's see who all is there on the live
chat. Let's see who is there. The world
teach you the world teacher Jagat Guru
Swami Veanandanda Abhuda Singh Dave
Ashwini Swami Jane Suas Chundra random
skull makan abhuda Singh Mr. Jam Vikas
PJ geopolitical dubet IMAT tested
beneath freedom from outcome from Canada
Vladimir Putin Ram Ojas Kumar Vun Pajati
Rayan NC Penguin Danish Kajura Orbit and
Markets Nan Dish Anand Singh Kedar Pab
RPL Indian-American Tanmoy Chakraorti
Mr. Jam Dave Geopolitical once again
from Indor Sumit D
Ram Shukla Vin Divor Singh Pranam
Vikrant M9 Daksh Rayan
Arindam Das Raav Aurora Separ
from Bangalore
Shiva Balaji Shre Singh Raat Shanks
all right subat shukla hello Anka G good
evening Herman Manuin hi. Beneath is
saying hi from Antarctica. Aayush Singh
Abi Chandel 005.
Harley Diddi Sun. Well, interesting
name. Gautam Sonat Ojasit Kumar
Saiyi Kitchen. Okay. Uh Swami Jan from
Jaipur. Rdra Kumal Vun Nova Random
Shorts.
Imbred Hacker.
Okay. Really interesting name. Samir
Kachu. Namaskar. So Jata Saha from
Singapore. Good evening ma'am.
Ramachandra Vidad. Namaste G. Himman
Shusain. Oo. Okay. All right. Okay. So
let's take questions.
Let's take some questions. What
questions do we have? We already have
some super chats who already waiting for
me before I even started. Let's go with
those. Ash says, okay, first of all a
reminder to everyone. I will only take
geopolitics questions today. Just
putting it out there. Let's not discuss
other things today. So Ashotosh says,
given the massive hard power
differential, are we destined to become
a vasal state of the US or do you
believe India can truly rise to the
occasion and push through the sweeping
sweeping reforms needed?
Is India destined to be to become a
vasal state of the US? Well, that's what
the US wants. The US is trying
everything in its power to make India a
vasal state. And that's see right now on
the geopolitical chess board India is
the biggest piece that's up for grabs.
Okay. And the US wants it. Obviously the
Chinese are not in a position to
vasalize India. Russia has never
vasalized India or tried to vasalize
India. The US wants to vasalize India.
And the best way to do that is to apply
all kinds of pressure on India. Immense
pressure from various directions. Create
a fence of thorns around India. East
Pakistan, West Pakistan, Nepal. Now they
wanted the Bagram air base in
Afghanistan which can target three
countries minimum, India, China and Iran
and and much more. And if Afghanistan is
not willing to give Bram air base then
then bring fire to Afghanistan through
Pakistan and so much more. So the US
does want India to become a vasal state,
complete vasal state, another Japan kind
of thing. That's what they want. Is
India destined to be one? It all depends
on the leadership of India. It is not
good for India to be a vasal state of
the of the US because eventually we will
well go down the drain. Right? That's
what happens. That is the fate of all
vasals. Eventually they are used and
once they they they are no longer of any
use they are thrown away
and not just thrown away, balconized.
The British did that to us and this
could happen to us again if you're not
careful. So it will all depend on the
leadership. The current leadership,
Prime Minister Modi, is
determined not to allow India to be
vasalized, which is why we are facing
more problems now. All the problems go
away if we become a vasal. There are
people who are asking on XO that Mr.
Modi has such a bad foreign policy. Such
a terrible foreign policy. Look at Dr.
Manm Singh. When Dr. Manm Singh was
prime minister, India US relations were
so good, so smooth.
Yeah, when Pakistan did 2611, India did
not even respond. Obviously, relations
will be good. If we are not a threat, if
we are a nation without ambition, if we
are a nation without any economic
prospects, military prospects, obviously
relations would be good. We were not a
nation that mattered. India did not
matter anywhere. Which is why the US
treated us with benign neglect.
Today, India matters.
That's why the US has a very different
approach towards India. So that's the
deal. So my then the question is can
India truly rise to the occasion through
sweeping reforms? I am not sure about
that. Sweeping reforms. What reforms do
we need? End reservations.
If India has to achieve its potential,
we have to end reservations, cast based
reservations. Does the current
government have the
the the
wherewithal to do that? To say it
politely? I'm not sure about that.
India needs educational reforms, deep
educational reforms.
Does the current government have the
wherewithal, the cohes to do that? I'm
not sure. So we may perhaps not become a
vasal, but will we rise to the potential
to our true potential and become a
genuine world power? I am not sure about
that. Does the current government have
the capacity to to bring in those
sweeping reforms? Without those reforms,
nothing changes in India.
Without making India merit-based
society, nothing changes in India. India
will remain mediocre otherwise. So, I
don't I'm not sure about that. But
probably as long as Mr. Modi is in
power, India will not become a vasal.
ICMBB says, "Is the new H1B change the
best chance for India to tackle its
eternal tragedy of the commons brain
drain problem?" We are all guilty, sir.
Everyone's guilty. So, you don't have to
say that I'm guilty myself. Everybody
wants to leave this country.
Everybody if given the chance will leave
the country. Very few people actually
have the chance, have the opportunity,
have the means but don't leave the
country. Very few people like that
exist. We I'm sure we all know a few of
those.
Some of us may be those. So now um this
H1B
thing that this the Trump administration
has done
$100,000
is the apparently the onetime fee that
has to be paid. Yesterday uh that fellow
whoever his name is the guy standing to
the right of Trump he was saying it's a
yearly payment annual payment then the
US government says no it's a one-time
thing and it will not affect certain
people they are intentionally creating
chaos they intentionally spreading
misinformation the guy standing to the
right of Trump his own minion is saying
it's an annual thing then they go on
Twitter the government the US government
and says no it's not annual to make it
clear your guy said on live TV next
standing next to Trump and Trump did not
correct him and then you come and say
it's not an annual thing. They are
intentionally purposefully spreading
confusion. And who's the victims? The
Indian-Americans mostly 70% of the H1Bs
are Indian-Americans. So yeah, there not
even Indian-Americans, Indians who are
on that visa. Not really
Indian-Americans.
So the point is this is devastating
potentially for Indians who have this
great dream of settling in the US. So
what Indians do is this. You take a big
loan 50 lakh rupees loan and you send
your child to the US to study on a
master's degree or something and you
then spend the rest of your life paying
off that loan. But the hope is that your
your child will get a master's degree
there and then somehow they will get a
job in the US through H1B and then over
over the next 15 20 years they'll become
they'll get a green card and then become
a citizen. So your entire your child's
entire life the entire young adult life
from the age of 25 to about 45 or 50 is
spent in this chakra of hoping for a
green card and then citizenship. I what
kind of life is that? Horrible. I know
plenty of people personally who are in
that circle who are eternally waiting
for that for the next phase of the of
the immigration process to happen and it
is purposefully slowed down for Indians.
If you are born in Europe, the
immigration process is fast like that. I
would know. But if you are born in
India, my goodness, they will slow
everything down. So if it takes let's
say 1 year for a for a person in Europe
who was born in Europe, it'll take at
least 10 times that that time period for
Indians. So because of this new H1B visa
policy, is it a is it the best chance
for India to tackle its eternally
eternal tragedy? Brain drain? No. I mean
yes.
Yes. But no,
potentially no. Yes, definitely.
So how does India tackle this tragedy?
The tragedy is that all Indians who have
some brain want to leave India and
settle down in the in the US or some of
the western country. They want to escape
the ghastly living standards that you
have in India. The corruption that
allegedly plagues all levels of you know
most levels of government. allegedly
allegedly
um
you know cast cast based reservations
very few job opportunities and career
prospects all of that that plagues India
Indians want to want to escape that
which is why they go to the west mainly
the US now that the US doesn't want
Indians clearly
what happens will India be able to
resolve this brain drain issue no
the Indians who want to escape will
escape instead of the US they'll go
somewhere They'll go to the UK, they'll
go to Germany, they'll go to France,
they'll go to Russia, they'll go to
China, they'll go to Australia, they'll
go to Singapore, they'll go somewhere.
If they want to escape, they'll escape.
It is this doesn't mean that the brain
drain will be reversed. For the brain
drain to reverse,
India has to tackle some very deeprooted
problems.
The alleged corruption that that
permeates allegedly many levels of
governance.
allegedly.
Who wants to deal with that? Most
Indians will leave because of that.
Those who can.
The fact that you know there are very
few job opportunities in India.
You want to do you want to have a career
in in in quantum computing, you want to
have a career in in nanotechnology, you
want to have a career in whatever. Do
you have prospects in India? And if
prospects exist, how big are the
prospects?
Do you have the opportunities in India
to really
flourish and bloom to the highest to the
best of your potential? Do you have it
in India? Does India give those
opportunities?
And what about all the reservations and
all that all that nonsense?
So the the the
opportunity exists,
but will the the govern government grab
the opportunity? Will they have the
wherewithal to end these problems?
better living standards which which will
which necessitates a war on the alleged
corruption that's allegedly everywhere
allegedly
h does the government have the
wherewithal to do that can they end the
reservations
can they make India purely merit-based
society like China
that tragedy continues so
Rohan says do you do you disagree with
Scott Galloway that big tech like Apple
and Google act act as IP landlords
buying MSME tech and claiming credit
without innovating. I don't disagree. I
don't disagree with him.
I don't disagree with him.
All right.
Okay. Sugata Saha. Well, thank you
ma'am. Thank you for becoming a member.
You're very kind. Thank you ma'am.
And please welcome the new member. Thank
you ma'am. Aris Manticor says Islamic
NATO US proxy an outer ring of them. Of
course, it's not really a US NATO. Look
at NATO. Look at the actual NATO. What's
the actual NATO? It's a bunch of
European countries, Western European
countries, plus Canada plus the US.
Right? That's what it is. And the actual
NATO, North Atlantic Treaty Organization
has one single hgemonic power who is the
overlord of everybody else. Undisputed
leader. Who's that? It's the United
States.
Correct. The United States is the
undisputed leader of NATO. Nobody even
dreams of challenging the US for the top
position.
Now, if you want to create an Islamic
NATO,
you would need multiple nations to
become members of this organization or
alliance. Right now, it's just Saudi
Arabia and Pakistan. Secondly, do you
have an undisputed leader in the Islamic
in the Islamic world? There are multiple
aspiring leaders. Saudi Arabia obviously
is the homeland of Islam. Secondly,
Turkey wants to be the leader of the of
the Islamic world. Then thirdly, you
have Iran who wishes to be the leader of
the Islamic world. And then Pakistan who
says that we are the only Islamic
nuclear power. We should be the leader.
There are four nations who who are
jousting for the top position and nobody
is going to give up their aspirations.
So you don't even have a clear leader.
You don't have any hedgemen. How can you
have an Islamic NATO even if more
nations join it? So what that tells you
is that this is actually a US
orchestrated thing.
If Saudi Arabia and Pakistan create a
treaty, an alliance of mutual
self-defense,
it cannot happen without an ashiad, a
blessing from the US.
And maybe the Saudis don't really want
Pakistan to be in alliance with them,
but the Americans have told them the
Saudis depend heavily on the US for
national security, for defense, and for
political stability. If the US wants,
Saudi Arabia can be in terrible turmoil,
Saudi Arabia has to do what the US says.
Pakistan is even more dependent on on
the US. They obviously also have to do
what the US says. So the US says, "Okay,
you you get together and that's what's
happened, right?" So that is the deal,
right? Divor Singh says, "I live close
to an air force base and I see Dnur
Singh is watching is is observing UFOs.
I see American planes making impossible
moves in the air at all times. It's
almost an open secret here in Arizona
making including making 180° turns super
fast." Well, that's a really interesting
observation. I mean last year in the in
the last quarter of last year there was
this this spate of UFOs
over New Jersey and I saw some of the
videos that that came out on social
media. These UFOs these UAPs now they've
rebranded UFOs to UAPs and some of the
UAPs or UFOs looked like aircraft. They
made they even made the the noise the
sound of jet engines and all and then
some of them would suddenly transform
into orbs.
which doesn't really follow the laws of
physics that we are familiar with. But
you know like Arthur C. Clark said any
sufficiently advanced technology is
indistinguishable from magic. So
So now you are reporting that you
actually observe this in real time. You
observe this. It's in kind of an open
secret in Arizona.
Um where is that that place Area 51?
It's not in Arizona, is it? It's in
Nevada, is it? It's It's somewhere in
that region, that arid part of the US,
southwestern US. Uh,
so yeah. So, what's really most likely
happened is that this is advanced
military technology and it's so advanced
possibly that, you know, it looks to
most people like it's UFOs. See for
example there was this very famous air
crash that happened in Roswell New Mexi
Mexico probably 1947 I think I don't
remember which year exactly probably 47
and there was this report the there was
this bunch of reports in the US media
that a flying saucer had crashed and the
reports were very quickly covered up and
the US military said air force said that
this was a crashed air balloon weather
balloon or something
and the eyewitnesses had had reported
that the craft looked like this
boomerang shaped thing or something
similar and that kind of is very similar
to a a very peculiar design that had
emerged out of Germany, Nazi Germany,
the Horton brothers.
They had this flying wing design for
aircraft which is something that uh that
Loheed Martin or whoever copied to
create the the the stealth bomber, the
first stealth bomber. So the Nazis were
far far advanced, way more advanced than
everybody else. And it's possible that
the Americans were were were possibly
test flying one of those aircraft and it
crashed in Roswell, New Mexico. And it
was so futuristic that people thought it
was a flying saucer. So if that's what
that was the situation in 1947, imagine
what it is now. So it's possible that
there's there are entire branches of of
applied physics that have been
essentially hidden away from the public.
And it's possible that the that there is
very advanced technology that is
actually uh in possession of the US and
uh some of it will be used for creating
flying objects which will appear to
break the laws of physics.
So yeah I think it's it's not UFOs that
you're witnessing. It's it's maybe
Loheed Martin or something technology
advanced technology secretive
technology.
Okay. Hey, Dn Singh says this is not a
historical question. I went to San
Diego. Saw Star of India, an old ship
which is very famous. What's up with
that? I am not aware of it. Star of
India. What I know is that India had a
very India was the first maritime
civilization. And until the period of
the British occupation, India had a very
I mean very advanced ship building
industry. Some of the ships that
participated in the US war of
independence
and the US civil war were made in India.
I believe that the ship on which the US
national an anthem was written was also
made in India.
So maybe the Star of India is one of
those. Let's let's if you want let's
quickly Google that. What is the Star of
India ship in San Diego? Let's see.
Star of India, San Diego.
What is this ship?
It's the world's oldest active sailing
ship. Iron Hold ship. Salmon holder.
And why is it called the Star of India?
It doesn't tell you why.
And so on. Uh, US national
anthem. Ship. Ship. Was it written on a
ship? The star spangled banner was
written about a British ship HMS mindon
whatever it is it was built in Bombay
India by Mr. Vadia a parci ship builder.
There you have it. So yeah. So I'm not
sure about the star of India but India
and the US have this ancient connection
there.
Okay. Next. Bascar purohit says in some
army circles we gave hint some in army
circles gave a hint that we acquired 10
to 12 warheads per year since 2014. But
some say every gram of highly enriched
uranium is tracked by international
agencies. If they clamped down on Iran
hard, how did Barat do it?
Okay, look, I have absolutely no idea of
how many warheads we are acquiring per
year. Uh, since whenever. But let's say
that what you are saying is true. Since
2014, 10 to 12 warheads we are adding to
our stockpile.
Um, so let's say we had 100 warheads in
2014. We are adding let's say 10 per
year. It's been 11 years. So 110. So
maybe so by that from that perspect
using those calculations we would have
about 210 or so at least warheads by now
and I'm not sure about highlyenriched
uranium. Well it does it mean that we
are infiltrated and the international
agencies know exactly how much highly
enriched uranium we have in the country?
I doubt it. I don't think we are that
badly infiltrated by international
agencies.
And also let's not let's not forget that
our bombs may not be highly enriched
uranium uranium bombs. Our warheads may
employ plutonium. Plutonium has lots of
advantages over highly enriched uranium.
You need way less plutonium compared to
uranium to have uh to have a viable
nuclear weapon. Plutonium has a much
smaller
uh you need a much smaller amount of
plutonium for it to go critical or
supercritical which is the threshold of
a nuclear explosion. So yeah I don't
know about I can't speculate
I can't speculate about this. I I don't
have any connections in agencies.
I don't have any connections in army
circles who can talk talk to me about
warheads and all that. So I have no
idea. Can't speculate sir. Ojaswit says
how relevant was India in geopolitics in
1980s 1990s irrelevant mostly even in
2014 India was irrelevant
today it's relevant yeah what see you
are relevant in geopolitics if you are
powerful if you are really powerful if
you have the ability to disrupt the
world order shipping lanes whatever
India did not have that ability of
course for for for once in 1971 we
showed a flash of brilliance and we
bifurcated Pakistan And so then India
suddenly became relevant and then we
went to sleep again. 74 we test the
nuclear weapon and then we go to sleep
for 24 years. We shove it. Sh keep it on
the shelf there. Keep it there. Right.
It's only for display. What the hell? So
India was irrelevant in geopolitics.
Godliness says just now the crown states
US a Canada Australia and more have
recognized the so well the Palestine
state. Okay. Interesting. The US under
Trump is totally against this. But UK,
Canada, Australia have recognized it.
Um, crown states are revoling under the
Trump administration against the Trump
administration. Let's let's Google this.
Um, Palestine
Palestine
recognition.
Do we have any news live updates?
Canada, Australia, and the UK recognize
Palestinian statethood. So why have
three American vasals recognized the
Palestinian statethood? UK, Canada and
Stria officially rec announced
recognition of Palestinian statethood.
Uh UK politics live crown states.
Uh what's the news saying Starmer is
going to announce it? MPM Abbas
and what does Israel say about this?
What will recognizing Palestine as a
state? Okay, I'll not go into all that
speculation that that will be now done
there. So, this is breaking news.
Essentially, we are just hearing about
this. It's come in the last couple of
hours. It looks like that these nations,
the UK, Canada, and Australia have
recognized the state of Palestine.
So, what's it really do?
Does it actually give freedom to the
so-called state of Palestine? It does
not, right? uh it's it's a token action
like I always keep saying I've been
repeating myself uh never endingly that
there's a gigantic difference between
words and actions
words and actions so they are saying
okay we officially recognize it that's
words are they going to do something to
create the actual state of Palestine are
are they going to take some action
against Israel and force Israel to
withdraw from what they call Palestine
the state of Palestine wherever it
exists apparently I don't think they're
going to do that.
So maybe this is uh you know if you want
to control a situation you want to
control both sides of the situation if
you want to control the Indian
independent struggle if you are British
you have to be supporting the British
side as well as the Indian independent
side but ensure that you prop up leaders
from the Indian independent side who are
completely passive and nonviolent
that way it is a it is a independence
movement only in name it doesn't really
take any actual action to bring
independence to India I Imagine an
Indian independence leader who goes and
tells the people of India tomorrow
morning wake up and your job only job is
to go and kill one English man then go
home your job is done you have 24 hours
to find one Englishman and kill him
that's it one English occupier who is
worse than the Nazis so it's fine to
kill such people right foreign occupiers
if that had been done by some Indian
leader within 24 hours India would have
been free but our leaders were
nonviolence and pacivity.
So the point is that this doesn't really
make any difference. Um maybe it's just
a ploy to be on both sides of the of the
issue and control everything. I don't
really see this making any difference to
uh I don't see it really having the
effect of actually creating the state of
Palestine. Right? That won't happen.
Basarit says India if India did not go
down the blenders of Mr. Gandhi and Mr.
Neu, UN security seat and so on. In
hindsight, would we not be in a US
wasal-like position today? It all
depends like I keep saying on the
leadership.
If someone is offering us something, a
powerful, genuinely powerful position
with veto power and we take it, it
actually puts us in a position where we
are less likely to become a vasal if we
have the right right leadership.
If the US offers us nuclear technology,
nuclear weapons technology, then we can
consider it based on whether any strings
are attached.
Does it mean that you also have to
create an have to give America a
military base in India? Is it that sort
of condition with which you will get a
nuclear weapon? Then you should say no.
But if they are just giving us nuclear
weapons to uh to create a counterweight
to China without any strings attached
then we should have taken the
technology. So it all depends on the
leadership and how they assess the
threat situation and what kind of risk
benefit analysis they do.
>> Right? It's not necessary that even if
we had taken what the Americans were
offering us, we would have become a
vasal. Not necessary.
We could have done it in a in a way that
was mutually beneficial. It all depends
on the leadership.
That's the point.
Divor Singh says, "I toured one of the
retire retired aircraft carriers of the
US Navy and they are bigger than any
other ship I have ever seen and these
are the most dangerous ships." So even
the retired aircraft carriers of the US
were pretty big, very large. Um, an
aircraft carrier by definition has to be
large enough so that aircraft can land.
And there were times when even the C130,
the C130 transport aircraft could land
on non-nuclear US aircraft carriers.
Let's let's Google it. Am I pulling this
out of my backside? This this story.
C130 landing on American aircraft
aircraft carrier. C 130 Hercules
landing on you landing on aircraft
carrier. Did it ever happen? Yes sir, it
did happen. So and these were non-
nuclear or non-nuclear
non-nuclear aircraft carrier.
Yes, the C-31 Hercules can land on a
non-uclear aircraft carrier. So today
you will have Yeah. Suppose for example
the USS Forestal which is obviously
retired now. This is a nonuclear
aircraft carrier. So you had these
conventional aircraft carriers that were
not even nuclear which were which means
that they were not as large as today's
super carriers and even on those ships
you could have the C C130 Hercules that
could land on it. So the these were
immense ships even when they were
non-uclear and today's nuclear aircraft
carriers are genuine super carriers like
football field sized aircraft. So yeah
indeed gigantic ships and they carry
immense firepower in the in the in the
shape of not just the aircraft that uh
are aboard but also the missiles
that they carry the depth charges and uh
anti-ubmarine warfare munitions that
they carry and and much more super
dangerous ships.
Rohan Allan says why Kaashv have not
climbed scientific why Kailash see we
are discussing geopolitics sir I said at
the very beginning I will only take
questions from geopolitics
there is no geopolitical significance of
kailash and no scientific significance
of kailash it has civilizational
significance all right so we will not
take this question today sorry sir MK
says when did the US deep state take
control of the US well I would say it
will be before 1963
before 1963 exactly when well that would
have been a creeping takeover maybe
maybe the time when the US federal
reserve was formed and it became a
private entity perhaps around that time
early 1900s
I can't really pinpoint the location in
in in the temporal history of the US uh
but definitely before 1963
Divor Singh says American youth is
getting radicalized really fast all over
the world I see fighting age men getting
polarized. It looks like the Balkans
everywhere. Does it look like the time
before the First World War? Kind of. It
does, doesn't it? Kind of does. The US
has never been as fragmented as as as it
is right now. It almost looks like we
are back the US is back to the to the
1840s or something or 1850s. You know
what happened after the 1850s, right? I
think everyone knows that.
Yeah. So uh the US is getting
radicalized. The American youth the
American see it's it's kind of like the
perfect storm. The US educational system
has been declining. It's been slowly
degrading since the 1950s and60s. I
think it was at its peak in in terms of
quality around 1950 1960. After that it
starts declining. There's this radical
left takeover of the US education system
of the US universities and colleges. And
today you will find lots of American
youth who don't who can hardly read or
li write at the third fourth grade
level. That's how bad it is. There are
people who have absolutely no
understanding of the world outside of
their little bubble. You ask them the
what's the capital of Australia? They
will say they have no idea. If you ask
them to point out where is Mongolia on
the map, they'll not know where it is.
That sort of thing. Absolutely no
understanding of the world. They they
can hardly spell their own names. And
when you are a a person who has come up
through that kind of education system,
you have no ability to think critically.
You have no ability to discern what's
right, what's wrong, and make your own
judgments of what's right or what's
wrong. So you look for guidance outside.
You look for guidance elsewhere. You
look for some role model, someone who
appeals to you, someone who resonates
with you emotionally and then you you
listen to that person and whatever that
person has to say and then you absorb
all of that whatever the person is
saying. This is called secondhand
secondhand thinking.
So most of the thoughts and beliefs in
and all of that that Americans have it's
not something they have they have they
have uh come come upon themselves. They
have not thought it through. They have
simply absorbed someone's dogma. Dogma
is is essentially secondhand thinking,
the product of somebody else's thinking.
So, everyone is is filled with dogma.
And whoever they find that appeals to
them in some way, they they they kind of
believe what they say. And that's how
you you have this polarization of
society. there's either the left
liberals or the or the right-winger the
MAGA crowd and there may be some other
factions who are much smaller in number.
So especially if you have been through
higher education, college or university
level education, you if you have gone
through that, there's a very high chance
you're going to be a left liberal.
Um and that's the situation. So the
American youth is genuinely like super
polarized, super radicalized
and uh this sort of thing is happening
in Europe also.
So there's tremendous polarization
everywhere. True.
And uh the US looks like like I said
kind of back to its 18 1850s moment
1840s 1850s and the rest of the world
especially western Europe etc is being
swamped with immigration the people are
helpless there's nothing they can do
everything is is being done through
Brussels Brussels is or orchestrating
all these immigration policies and uh
the people feel helpless maybe there'll
be some spark somewhere that could who
knows but the problem is that during the
first world war you had lots of
genuinely independent nations
nation states and they all had agendas
of their own and they were all waiting
since essentially since 1871 to for the
right moment to take action to to
achieve whatever their agenda demanded.
So these nations were all genuinely
independent. Some of them formed blocks
and coalitions and and so on. But today
in Europe you have no independent
nation, no sovereign nation at all in
Europe.
They are either part of the EU or NATO
or both. which means they are not
sovereign. So they're helpless. The real
power in in Western Europe is the US
and in the east you have Russia. So the
world is going back to the imperial
system and that's the situation kind of.
Yeah. So
Dn Singh says why did the US pull out of
NATO article 5? Um I'll have to look it
up. What is NATO article 5 and what what
is this? Uh NATO article 5. What is
that?
NATO
article
what's five what's it say an armed
attack against one or more members will
be okay the that thing is the US part of
that USA
what's the deal
u obligates the US another has US pulled
out US pulled out really
really us pulled out NATO invoked I'm
not Sure, the US has pulled out of it.
Can Europe still count on
Trump has threatened to withdraw the US
from NATO and all? I'm not sure if the
US has pulled out of NATO article 5. As
long as you're a member of NATO, you
have to abide by all the articles of me
of NATO. You can't pick and choose and
cherrypick which article you will accept
and which you will not accept. That
doesn't work. It doesn't really work
like that. As long as you are a treaty
member of NATO, you have to abide by all
the articles. I'm not sure if the US has
pulled out of article five. To do that,
you have to pull out of NATO itself, I
would say. Okay. Dan Dave says, "I'm on
H1. I make 300,000 plus here as a as a
senior project manager. H1 will remain
on paper. H1 visa holders will simply
leave because of the chaos anarchy for
visa holders." And that's what it looks
like. There's this this this tremendous
confusion right now that the Trump
administration has purposefully created.
Um
what's his name? The that the guy
Trump's minion
Lutnik Lutnik, right? Howard Lutnik. He
said yesterday
on live TV that there's going to be an
annual fee of $100,000 for each H1B
visa. He said that standing one foot
away from Trump and Trump did not
correct him.
So he's he's standing next to the
president of the US, he's saying that's
going to be an annual fee of $100,000.
And Trump's nodding, yeah. And then next
day, the what what Pam, whatever her
name is, whatever that lady, the
spokesperson, she says, to be clear,
there is no such thing. But the guy
standing to the right of the president
said it's a it's a thing. So they are
purposefully sowing chaos
right and obviously in the US as we know
right now this there is this tremendous
anti-India sentiment that has been
engineered over the past two or three
years. I pointed this out in 2022. In
2022, after the special military
operation began in Ukraine and India
refused to participate in American and
Western sanctions on Russia, the the
West started this this outpouring of
vitriol against India on in the media
and on social media. So whether it is
UK- based uh media outlets like the BBC
like the Guardian whether it is Germany
based Deutschea or whatever whether it
is the New York Times or the Washington
Post or the New Yorker or whatever they
all started this outpouring of of
anti-India articles whether it's Rand
Corporation or think tanks or whatever
and you had a much lower level much much
baser level of anti-Indian propaganda
all across social media. So I pointed
out that this is going to be a big big
big problem for India. I said this in
2022 itself. You can watch my old old
live streams and videos in which I have
spoken about this multiple times. So
today the situation is that most
Republicans, most uh right-wing, most
conservative people in the US hate
Indians and the left has never liked
Indians. The Democrats, Indians
generally vote for the Democrats, but
the Democrats have no love for Indians.
Um, the US, I'll assure you, is a is a
deeply racist nation. It's a settler
colonial state founded on the genocide
of brown-skinned people. And you
Indians,
us Indians are brownkinned people. We
aren't white. The US is a deeply
fundamentally racist country.
Okay? Uh, just read their declaration of
independence.
What does the declaration of the
independence of independence say? What's
it say about the natives?
the savages, savage Indians, right? So,
this is like an like a Hindu exclusion
act all over again. What this H1B visa
thing and uh yeah, so there's going to
be chaos, there's going to be anarchy,
there's going to be more and more
anti-Indian hate and it just makes sense
for Indians to no longer go to the US, I
would say. So, yeah, take your business
elsewhere. I'm sure if you are a
highquality professional uh the world is
out there for you and you can go and uh
you know do well elsewhere.
Divoru Singh says in a pure war scenario
will Saudi Arabia now have to stand
against India. I doubt if Saudi Arabia
will actually come to Pakistan's aid uh
in a material sense if there's a a
resumption of operation hind or
something similar. Look, there is a
mutual defense treaty. No question about
it now. So, it's official. It's I'm I'm
sure the Saudis did not really want this
to happen. They they had no intention of
doing it, but the Americans told them to
do it. And you can't say that no to to
the to the overlord. So, there's this
mutual defense treaty now. So, what does
what's it going to really mean in in in
in real terms,
the way I see it, the US wants to
strengthen Pakistan's defense
preparedness. The Pakistani military is
kind of weak right now. They got
hammered during Operation Sundu in just
three days. No matter what they claim 6
and all the all the BS. Pakistan got
hammered really bad. We saw all of those
videos on YouTube on on social media on
Twitter, right? All those missile
strikes landing in the heart of
Pakistan, Nur Khan Air Base and Kirana
Hills and Rahul Pindi and that that
cratered airfield and all that. Do did
you see a single such video from
emerging from India anywhere? No. So
Pakistan is in a bad situation. If
there's a war with India, they're going
to get hammered and balconized. The
Americans need Pakistan as a
counterweight to India. They need
Pakistan as a troublemaker, potential
troublemaker to be deployed at any on on
demand against India. So for that, you
have to prop up Pakistan. You have to
strengthen Pakistan. You have to supply
Pakistan with funds. You have to supply
Pakistan with military equipment. Now
Pakistan is a terror terrorist nation
that that harbored Osama bin Laden. So
you can't do it openly otherwise the US
public will question Trump what the hell
are you doing Trump this is not why we
why we voted for you. So then the simple
answer is you route it through Saudi
Arabia. So I think Saudi Arabia will
will serve as a conduit for American
military equipment and American funding
to Pakistan or maybe the Americans will
just tell the Saudis to send to give
their own money to Pakistan. Whichever
way it works that's the role Saudi
Arabia will play. If there's a war I
don't think Saudi Arabia will be
involved directly. Maybe they will send
funds. They'll say send oil. Maybe they
will send more weapons to Pakistan. But
I don't expect Saudi soldiers to go to
two against Indians. I don't expect that
to happen.
MK says Israel is a sovereign country
then who and why etc. orchestrated
Israeli judicial reform protests. Can we
kick out Starling now as relations hit
bottom? I think Starling needs to be
revisited. We can't have stalling in
India. If Israel is so is a sovereign
country who orchestrated 2023 Israel
judicial reform protest maybe the
Israelis did it themselves who knows who
knows
maybe they did not want Netanyahu
and you can see that now there is no
protest against Netanyahu what happened
to the trial that corruption trial
against Netanyahu it's all very quiet
now he has proved his worth
so no trial no protests now the
judiciary is pleased everybody is
pleased so you can Everything is fine
now. But from about Starling, I
completely agree with you. Starling
needs to be kicked out. We can't have
Starling in India. Arian Thus, thank you
sir. Thank you very much. DNS Singh
says, "Does India have its own UAPs?"
Well, I haven't seen any any personally.
I hear rumors of of such
activities sometimes happening in the
far north of India and the Himalayan
region etc. But um I don't know. I'm not
sure that we have our own UAPs. I I
don't see any reports coming out on
social media or any such thing. See,
today everybody has a cell phone.
Everyone can take at least a bloody kind
of image if there's a UAP somewhere. And
you sometimes see people taking videos
of of uh missile launches, rocket
launches and so on whenever they happen.
The contrails, glowing contrails,
whenever there is some kind of re-entry
of space debris like what happened a
couple of days ago or over or DIY and
Noida, people take videos and the videos
flood social media. So the people of
India are ever ready with their cell
phones, right? But you don't see videos
of UAPs or UFOs emerging out of India.
So looks like we don't have that as far
as I can tell.
Sam is a new member. Thank you so much,
sir. And welcome to membership. Thank
you so much. Appreciate that.
In 1991, what was my reaction when the
USSR dissolved in 1991? I was an
immature child
and I was I was very very taken with
American propaganda.
So I was like yes the evil empire has
dissolved. The world is now free and
democratic. That's what I believed at
the time. You see you you learn you
evolve.
Many of the beliefs you have they change
over time and they should. Otherwise
you're not learning. You're not you're
not growing.
In in 1991 when the Americans invol in
invaded Iraq, I was like why isn't India
getting involved? We should be on the
right side of the world. Saddam Hussein
is this evil dictator. We should be
taken out. That's what I believe is is
this silly, naive, immature child.
I was at the time deep into my study of
history and whatnot. But I still did not
have the patterns. I could not see the
patterns yet. I could not really tell
what's right and what's wrong.
at that time, right? So, yeah, I was a a
naive, immature, silly
child and I was like, "Yes, USA the best
country in the world. Kennedy best
president." Yes, sir.
USSR evil. Saddam Hussein said, "Damn
it."
Okay. Arvinda Shinasan says outcome for
the for the country if from the 11th
instead of NCERT texts like Holiday
Resnik Atkins Thomas calculus etc
introduced along with Klausowitz and
little heart in martial arts training
it'll be a transformative thing for
India I mean I don't understand why we
wallow in mediocrity I recently saw some
textbooks for the 10th standard for
mathematics those textbooks are
atrocious
they they gave give me a headache. How
do you teach with those textbooks?
If you want to do algebra and and number
systems and and what they call Surds,
which is irrational numbers and and
whatever, why do you treat teach it in
the wrong order and with so little
problem solving? How on earth do you
expect children to understand?
The simplest thing is give kids the Shom
series book on on introductory algebra
and whatn not introductory trigonometry
and geometry you don't need anything
else why do you have to reinvent the
wheel and that to create an inferior
wheel so I would say if you do if we do
this if we introduce all the sham series
books as the text books that will
transform see if you have the sham
series book okay I have a whole bunch of
sham series books over here I still have
my old ones. I have like basic stuff
like uh college algebra and whatnot. You
know, children level stuff. The point is
if you have a Sham series book and you
want to learn algebra, you don't need a
teacher.
You don't need a teacher. That book
teaches you everything. It holds your
hand and teaches you everything from A
to Zed.
It will put teachers out of business.
That's the problem. That's why they
don't introduce Tom series books in
India. You take Holiday Resnik and if
you have the the basic mathematical
understanding, you don't need a physics
teacher.
You don't even need Helenic for physics.
You can do you can take the books by
Shom for physics.
So the point you don't need Thomas
calculus. I have never seen Thomas
calculus. Go with Hel go with Sham
series calculus. They have a basic
calculus. They have advanced calculus
and whatever else tensor you don't need
tensors. The point is the best books in
the world exist. Just get those books
and give it to the kids.
And then if you also introduce martial
arts training, well, imagine how it will
weaponize the Indian minds, not just
mentally but physically. It will
transform India. But why will the
government of India do that? They won't
do it. We need reservations. We need all
this nonsense. We need to keep India
down and mediocre.
So frustrating.
Timbuktu panda says, "Should I innr be
backed by Bitcoin and gold standard?" I
am very very suspicious of Bitcoin and
all this stuff. Gold, sure, absolutely
gold is great.
Gold is the only real store of value
historically, even today. Bitcoin and
all one
one solar flare and all your Bitcoin is
fried. Okay. So, yeah, I don't I don't
trust Bitcoin. It's not a long-term
store of value. It's not. Gold is.
A known user says global left runs
narrative in every country. In India,
the push narrative of making citizens
feel more inferior. The Indian inferior
complex. It's it's it's it's perpetuated
by the education system, by your
textbooks, by your godamned professors
and teachers and also by the by the news
media and the and the entertainment
industry and all all that. The whole
society perpetuates this. It's a
self-perpetuating loop. So how will this
change? Will the left always remain
strong in and is collapse of the left
possible? Anything is possible. How will
it change? It'll change when India has
the right kind of leadership. Really
strong leadership? Anything is possible.
What is the left? The left is in India
at least the left is allegedly a set of
a bunch of mercenaries who who will work
for allegedly the highest alleged
bidder. Allegedly
that's the Indian left in in China. The
left is the Chinese Communist Party and
they are sup supreme patriots in in the
USSR. The left were the they the the
Soviet communist party, right? And they
were also patriotic. They they were not
they they executed traitors,
right? Uh but in India allegedly the
left is a bunch of alleged mercenaries
who alleged allegedly work for the
highest alleged foreign bidder. So,
so, so it will change if we have the
right leadership, when we have the right
leadership, strong ironinfested
leadership.
Is the collapse of the left possible? Of
course, it's possible. DNU Singh says,
"So, democracy has almost failed all
across the globe. Is a China like one
party ruled better or North Korea like
dictator or Stalin like socialism?" I
would say for for every country a
different every country depending on its
culture on its on its values should have
its own form of governance.
See we have done this experiment with
democracy.
Has it really worked out for India?
Think about see we have the oldest known
history of all cultures on the planet.
Think back to the times when India was
at its peak culturally,
civilizationally, economically. Before
the 1700s, India was the world's largest
economy. Uh I'm not claiming it. And
Madison Madison has shown it. The
American economist. Uh so
when what what were the times when India
was at as its pinnacle? you know overall
as a as a as a power you can think of
the various imperial periods the Moran
Empire the Koshan Empire the Gupta
Empire the Chola Empire the Marata
Empire and so on so what do all those
periods have in common Imperial rule
non-democratic rule but what kind of
imperial rule what is an imperial rule
it's a dictatorship with a with a
dictator which is the emperor but what
kind of dictatorship or or imperial
system did we have during all those
periods the Moran period the Kushan
period the Gupta period and so It was
dharmic dictatorship
right so for India that's what will work
best dharmic dictatorship which means a
benevolent dictator example of
benevolent dictator Lie Kuanu great man
ironfisted ruler but a great man who
spent his entire life dedicating himself
to the upliftment of his people and his
country that's what you need right so I
would say I would not say that we need
someone like Stalin
I would say we would need someone like
Vishnu Chanaga plus Chandra Gupta Moria
or Ashoka the great who was possibly
both of them combined into one or
perhaps someone like Kaneska the Koshan
one of the greatest Indians ever or
maybe someone like Scandupta or Chandra
Gupta II or maybe someone like
Chhatrapati Maharaj or someone like
Rajendra Chula that sort of thing right
someone who walks the path based on the
teachings of the Bhagwat Gita not Gita
Gita The the gith of Bhagwan who Sri
Krishna the man who said who tried his
best to avert war but when all attempts
failed he said kill them all the the
evil guys right. MK says is the
government of India aware of ministers
whose family members are western
citizens and how to handle it and how
will India now act on the next Dalai
Lama? Is the government of India aware
of something? Well, you have to ask the
government of India not me. I am not a
representative of the government of
India. So I am not the person to ask
this question sir.
I think whatever the situation is is is
look if everyone knows it I'm sure the
government of India also knows it by
government of India what do you mean?
What do you exactly mean by government
of India? Do you mean Shar Modi G? I
suppose Shar Modi G knows everything.
How to handle it?
That's for Shar Modi G to decide.
At least we can trust him, right? Uh how
will India act on the next Dalai Lama?
It will all depend on how China behaves.
We shall see. All right. We shall see.
It will behave. It will depend on
China's approach and attitude towards
the India China relationship over the
next coming period of time. India and
China are now both being targeted and
encircled by the US. So is Russia. The
US is h looks like it's hellbent on
creating RAIC. But how will China
approach this? How will China behave?
What is China's approach and attitude
going to be like depending on that? And
what do I mean by that?
I mean that if you want a constructive
India China relationship that can never
happen unless the core issue is resolved
which is the undemarcated India Tibet
border.
Will China show willingness to resolve
this in a in a certain time frame or
will they keep dragging their feet? If
they keep dragging their feet then to
hell with China. We'll we'll we'll see.
We'll we'll figure a way out because
without resolving this issue, you can
never normalize India China relations.
So it'll all depend on the approach of
China.
Vive Singh says the Ministry of Defense
is beating around the bush to buy the
IIAF squadrons. Why are we unable to
decide decide our way ahead? We are
stuck with air independent propulsion
and SSN submarine delays too. I think
the government of India needs to really
get it get its act together. It is
imperative that we transform ourselves
in over the next I wouldn't say 10 years
maybe 3 to 5 years maximum into a nation
with real teeth. real teeth.
For that we have to transform ourselves
into a very powerful
military equipation
and the navy is is a key component to
that and and we still have what 15
submarines what are we a joke of some
kind 15 submarines
so I think it's it's high time the
government gets its act together um I
would say see right now we hearing that
we are going to buy the rafal more
Rafals there is this very tempting offer
of the Sukoy 57 also I and we have the
Tjas mark 1A and the and the AMCA and
all that and the key to all of that is
the jet engine issue.
We have to find the the best way forward
and we cannot keep on dragging our feet.
The past 11 years we're waiting for for
an announcement for the next big
purchase or acquisition of a large
number of fighter planes. What on earth
is going on? So I'm sure the government
alone isn't the cause of the problem.
Maybe there are issues with the Indian
Air Force etc. also possibly whatever
the issues are. Resolve the issues. You
can't allow these procedural delays and
bureaucratic delays and whatn not and
some individuals potentially allegedly
whatever hypothetically to affect the
national interest and to hurt the
national interest.
So we need to resolve this jet engine
imglio at the earliest. We need to
acquire, I would say, 50 submarines,
build, buy, beg, borrow, steal,
whatever. We need at least 50
submarines, I would say. And and
whatever else. So, as a stop gap measure
before we can have the AMCA rolling out
in another 10 years, maybe set up
production lines of the Sukoy 57 as well
as the Rafal 44.5 whatever in India. Set
up two production lines. We already have
we are already you know
using Rafal aircraft. So we know how to
use those. So set up production lines
build 100 or so and build another 100
200 Sukoya 57s and acquire acquire the
technology if the Russians are offering
it and and that will al obviously help
us you know build derivatives of those
aircraft so we can build our own Sukoy
instead of 5767 or whatever eventually.
So that's what we need to do and that to
soon
divor Singh says today Germany says it
will command Europe if the US pulls out.
Some Germans say uncle H wasn't really
that bad.
Uncle Hard some of his speeches looks
like it's true. Was it 6 million or
271,000? Very controversial questions. I
have no idea. Was it 6 million or
271,000? I don't know. I grew up
believing that it was 6 million. As a
kid when I lived in Europe, I used to
watch these World War II documentaries
and I was like, "Yeah, German Nazis
killed six million Jews and only Jews,
nobody else." Later it emerges that at
least I don't know about a million plus
Romanis were killed apparently and the
numbers have been consistently
understated you know you know kind of
kind of that entire story is is has been
brushed under the swept under the carpet
and and Jews like Elie Wisel what's his
name Eli Wisel or whatever his name was
what what was it let me see Eli Elie
what's his name E L I E Wisel
this this gentleman
okay Romanianb born Jewish nobel laurate
etc and he tried to um tried to you know
kind of sweep the Romani thing under the
the carpet
Romani
oh nothing about this on Wikipedia
that's interesting nothing about this on
Wikipedia Eliisel Romani
Ro
Romani
Gypsy. What about it? So this entire
thing is now you will not find anything
about this remembering the Roma victims
of the Holocaust.
Okay. This this lady it it was claimed
she was Jewish. She was actually Romani
but her name was Satella Tinbach.
Okay. So
Eli.
Okay. So that entire story seems to have
been uh airbrushed out of existence. It
looks like
um
yeah so so you know Google won't show
you this now. Very interesting that
Google won't show you that. So there was
this this plan to create a vict a
memorial for the victims of the
Holocaust in the US somewhere during
Bill Clinton's time. And there was
they they had intended to also honor the
Romani victims of the Holocaust. And
this guy Eli Wisel was against that that
the Holocaust belongs only only to the
Jewish people and the Romanis don't
matter because they are brown, right?
That sort of thing. So yeah, there we
have it. Um so Germany says it will
command Europe if the US pulls out.
Okay. Well, let's see if Germany has any
leadership. Who's the current German
chancellor? the guy who went to the
White House and present presented uh the
birth certificate of Donald Trump's
grandfather or something, the guy who
saccepted the US, that guy.
Um
I don't think there's any leadership in
Germany today. So how if if there's no
leadership in Germany, how will they how
will they take over the leadership of
Europe? I don't see that happening. Some
Germans say Uncle H wasn't bad. Well,
some Americans also say Uncle H wasn't
bad, right?
And if you hear his speeches, see I
remember him those black and white
speeches. When you hear those when you
listen to those speeches in German, they
sound very aggressive. But when you
actually hear the listen to the
translations, he's not saying anything
aggressive at all. He's he's actually
saying that talking about policies and
whatnot, economic policy and all that.
Nothing about kill the Jews or whatever.
But it doesn't mean that he did not kill
the Jews. So we don't quite know what
the truth is. you know
a lot of propaganda a lot of narrative
stories and whatn not rit says the US is
powerful has vosalized so many countries
why can they still not dominate over
Russia like Russia destroyed Ukraine
can't we attack neighbor the Russia
Russians haven't destroyed Ukraine
Russia hasn't destroyed Ukraine go to
Kiev you can Kiev is okay
many of the Ukrainian cities are
completely intact the war is happening
on on the on the on the wheat fields of
Ukraine. It's not really h and in some
whatever
most of Ukraine hasn't been destroyed.
Uh the US is powerful. They can't still
dominate. Why can't they dominate
Russia? Because the Russians are also
powerful. They have more nuclear
warheads than the US. Simple. The
Russians are not they are not a doormat.
Defeating Russia isn't that easy. Russia
has more nuclear weapons and the means
to deliver those nuclear weapons than
the US. So Russia has taken the
precautions it needs to take. That's why
the US aren't able to dominate Russia.
Uh why can't we attack neighbors?
Because the our neighbors are assets of
the US. You yourself have mentioned sir
that the US has vasalized so many
countries. Well, if you look at east and
west Pakistan, these are US vasals.
Nepal is a newly minted US vasal. The US
is pressurizing Afghanistan to hand over
the Bram air base which will once again
vasize Afghanistan. So the Americans are
creating a ring of thorns around India,
a fence of thorns. Look at Myanmar. Look
at the disaster in Manipur. What is the
cause of the disaster in Manipur?
Project Kukan for Christ. Who is
orchestrating that?
So if you think that India is that
powerful that we can you can take over
attack and take over American vasals in
our neighborhood. Well, I've got some
news for you. We can't. You'll say, why
is India so weak? Look at China. They
want Taiwan. Taiwan is right next door
to the the Chinese. Can they take it?
They can't. That's how powerful the US
is. Please don't underestimate the how
powerful the US is and that will tell
you how powerful Russia also is.
Gallivor says need a thoughtful answer
not a politically correct one. I'm going
to give you diplomatic answers because I
have a life to live too. You have to be
able to understand what I'm saying. Now
what's the question? Is racial contempt
a weapon?
Mention the oath leading to 22nd June.
Are you talking about Nak what was 22nd
June 1941? Let me check it out. Okay. I
don't remember all the dates. I don't
memorize dates. Let's see. 22 June 1941.
What happened? Crystal Nak was it? It
was operation Barbar Roa.
22nd June 1941. Operation Barbarosa.
Okay. So what are you saying
leading to 22nd June 1941? What about
the Anglo-Saxons? Racial contempt. The
Anglo-Saxons are a sup supremely racist
people that you should know. See, let me
explain. You don't want a politically
correct answer. Let me give you a plain
answer.
Um,
the Germans
have this concept. Let me show you the
concept. Why are the Nazis evil? Why do
we consider the Nazis to be evil?
Because of one of the reasons is this
concept.
Libans
Libans the territory which a group state
or nation believes is needed for its
natural development. It's a German
concept of expansionism and focus
nationalism.
Um look
it was a German concept of expansionism.
So the Germans said that Germany the
nation the nation of Germany is not
enough territory. It's not enough space
for the German people to thrive in. We
need more land. We will take the land of
the Slavic peoples and we will settle
Germans there and that's going to be our
Libans,
the land that the German people need to
thrive. So we will take land from the
Slavic peoples. What will happen to the
Slavic people there?
That okay, we'll we'll kill them off or
we'll send them to Siberia, which is
another euphemism for killing them off.
So the Nazis were so evil they wanted to
take over the land of the Slavic peoples
to the east of Germany big more than
Germany land that is more than the
nation of Germany and they will get rid
of the people who live there eliminate
them and settle Germans there and that
how that's how Germany will thrive such
an evil concept right
now think about it the Nazis
so naturally we consider Nazis to be
evil because they have this evil concept
take someone's land, exterminate those
people and settle your people there.
Lebanon's how
now
the Anglo-Saxons
what did they do in North America?
They implemented the concept of lean
on a continental scale.
Not just in North America, also on
another continent called Australia.
They wiped out the natives of two
continents
and created Lebanon there.
They took the concept to a to and
implemented it on such a scale that the
Nazis could not even dream of such of
for such a scale.
The Anglo-Saxons.
Who's the original Nazis?
Am I being politically correct now?
And what was behind all of this? They
believe that they are superior. And the
and the brown-skinned people who lived
in these places, they they their life
was worth nothing. So they exterminated
between 50 to 100 million native
Americans and God knows how many native
Australians.
Yeah, there you have it.
Divor Singh says is a controlled
demolition happening of the US. They can
deconstruct the US and make it seem like
they lost power naturally to fool us. I
mean who's there?
Who is they? I don't think a control
demolition is happening right now. A
control demolition of Europe is
happening. That I that that I can see.
Europe is being deindustrialized.
All of that is being done through
Brussels. So Germany has shut down its
nuclear reactors. They have dismantled
their nuclear reactors. They now burn
coal.
What about global warming and all that
BS? What what happened there? So Germany
now no longer has access to plentiful uh
to a plentiful source of cheap energy
which you need for a large economy for a
manufacturing based economy that energy
was coming in from Russia Russian gas
that's not available anymore has been
detonated
and the whole of the European see there
are two major economies in Europe one is
Germany one is France how are they doing
not great Germany is going backwards
it's contracting and overall Europe is
not doing great at Europe is stagnating.
So economically Europe is kind of dead.
Geopolitically it's irrelevant.
Geopolitically it's not powerful. Now
they're going to put more more of the
bill of NATO, the more of the burden of
NATO. They're going to double their
expenditure their the share of the GDP
which goes to defense which will which
is going to prioritize American
interests in the region not their own
interests. Um they they none of the
nations are sovereign. All of the
nations are saddled with increasing
illegal immigration uh which which is
being done by Brussels. Brussels decides
how much immigration each nation needs
to take every year and you get only
certain flavors of immigrants military
age males from certain certain regions
of the world only. Right? So Europe is
being destroyed in this manner. We are
witnessing a controlled demolition of
Europe for sure. Now the same is
beginning to happen in Japan. So they're
going to bring in a whole bunch of god
knows what kind of people into Japan. I
can see a lot of Bangladesh is appearing
in Japan and god knows what other kind
of people appearing appearing in Japan.
And obviously the people of Japan don't
want that but who cares?
And when it comes to the US, the US is
increasingly polarized. The education
system is increasingly garbage. So the
American people can't think for
themselves anymore. and uh yeah so it
looks like the west is imploding in some
sense but it's all being done in a
precise calibrated manner
so who's who's doing all this I would
say well the the the finger of blame
would typically go towards the deep
state whatever that is right um then why
would you deliberately give up your
power you're not really giving up your
power but you're just transforming the
world the way it
And actually whoever could potentially
be your threats to you, those people
you're going to defang them.
Essentially, that's what it looks like.
Godliness says first the 50% tariff,
then the Saudi Pak deal, then sanctions
on Chabahar, now the H1B visa fee, now
discussion on Kata. What next? What's
next? Next eventually sanctions on
India. What next? IndiaPakistan war,
maybe Bangladesh, maybe Myanmar
weaponized further against the whole of
the northeast of India, maybe
Afghanistan is again under US occupation
and from there they can support
Pakistan. If you want Pakistan to go to
war to with India, then why don't you
you retake Bram air base which was under
your occupation for 20 years and create
a powerful American air base there. So
in case Pakistan gets hammered, they can
intervene.
India is being encircled right now.
This will will this stop? Will this go
further? It's going to go further. It's
going to go further, sir.
Sid says, "How long will it take us to
reach China's level of infrastructure,
durable roads, nationwide highspeed
rail, efficient drainage and lower air
pollution?" Look, highspeed rail, let's
take one example, highspeed rail. Well,
the first highspeed rail is coming up
between what? Mumbai and Ahmedabad, the
the bullet train, right?
um that started when close to a decade
ago the the the first construction of
the whole thing the beginning of the
construction of the project and then
there were delays in some parts of the
route for apparently political reasons
I'm not sure and u it'll still take
apparently a few years before the the
highspeed rail bullet train thing
becomes operational so this is what's
the distance between Mumbai and Amdawad
800 km let's go to the map and quickly
figure it out. What's the distance?
Um
800 or so kilometers. Let's quickly go.
Let's do a straight line distance
between Mumbai and Ahmedabad. Measure
distance roughly. Okay, it's not 800.
Excuse me. It's 450 km. That is tiny.
It's a short stretch of highspeed rail.
450 km. And that is taking like a decade
or something. at that speed. It's going
to take us a century to have half the
kind of coverage that China has. The
Chinese do things at a break neck speed,
not at a at a snail pace. So if you want
nationwide highspeed rail at the speed
at which things are going currently,
it's going to take you more than a
century.
You see
um durable roads. Well, if you go to
most Indian cities allegedly, you will
see that roads are rebuilt every year
allegedly.
Every year you build a new road. When
you lay the road again allegedly and
then a few weeks allegedly after the
road is relayed, some people will come
and start digging it up.
Government employees allegedly and they
will lay new pipelines or whatever
allegedly and then again re repatch the
road and now it's no longer straight and
it's all full of potholes and whatnot.
And then allegedly during each rainy
season the roads will disintegrate into
potholes and moonlike surface allegedly.
And the next year the process starts
again. This is money laundering
obviously right allegedly. So if if this
is and if this is allegedly the norm in
some parts of India, then it will take
essentially an infinite amount of time
for us to have uh the same sort of uh
level that China has of infrastructure,
durable roads, straight flat roads
without any potholes and whatnot. It can
be done. It can be done tomorrow if you
want. But for that you will have to
launch a war on the alleged corruption
that exists allegedly across India
allegedly.
Yeah. So I have no idea how long will it
take close to an infinite amount amount
of time the way things are right now.
Divor Singh says do you think a
conservative America is a stronger
America. I was personally in MAGA for a
while looks like everything is better in
general than the liberals.
Overall I think any nation if it is
conservative is more stable.
See what is the liberal movement? The
liberal movement is about rapid change
and moving away from the past. The
liberal movement is predicated on the on
the cons on on on on the belief or the
the the the
concept that
traditional
systems are oppressive in some manner.
Um it's all based on Marxist ideology.
So traditional systems are the the
systems that are rooted in tradition
that go go back centuries. Those
obviously constructs are all
oppressive constructs because they
marginalized the the the the
proletariat and they uplifted the
bourgeoisi
and uh they they gave rise to all these
lump elements and so on. So you to
dismantle that and you have to bring
everybody on the same same footing same
even level. So essentially that's the
the the foundation of the liberal
movement and you will see that in
liberal movements everywhere around the
world even the first liberal movement
that you can think of which is the
French revolution was all about
fraternity equality of people liberty
equality fraternity and obviously that
can only happen if you take lop the
heads of the the the the bois and the
royalty royal royalty right so the
liberal movement is all about that it's
about dismantling institutions it's
about dismantling social structures it's
about dismantling traditions
But what are you going to replace all of
that with? You're going to have to
replace institutions with new
institutions. But new institutions
create new traditions. And most people,
the average person needs some kind of
framework, moral, ethical, etc. And
religious framework based on which they
can live their life. Most people can't
think for themselves a priority from
first principles. Most people need that
guidance that comes from outside which
which is the role that religion and and
culture and tradition has has
traditionally played
and that's why
you know it it makes it makes people
ruthless. So it's a problem. If the
whole country is liberal, then it's a
country full of chaos and anarchy.
Which is why you will find that no
matter which country you are in even if
it's whatever the type of religion,
religious system etc. you have you know
conservative uh movements are generally
more stable and generally better
overall. So I know that MAGA from from
an Indian perspective MAGA isn't good
for India. the MAGA the people who who
the average MAGA person hates India
right they hates they hate brown people
they hate Hindus and so on which I'm
sure you would have realized at some
point in time that there is this
undercurrent that that flows below the
surface
uh but yeah overall it's better than the
liberals for the country itself not for
other countries possibly but for the
country for the US itself yeah okay
project smiling Buddha says assessment
about prime minister Modi's statement
our enemy is reliance on other countries
when did he say that did he say that
today he gave an address to the nation
today which I kind of briefly caught was
talking about GST rates and such so are
these words just words or some actions
that can be expected
I am I'm hopeful that actions will come
out of this see prime minister Modi is a
man of action that we know the action
may take time because of the the kind of
system that we have but he is a man of
action for sure that we can be pretty
certain about.
So if he has said that our enemy is our
reliance on other countries, I hope that
he is talking about uh technological
sovereignty there because the entire
nation depends on well platforms that
have been created by a country that is
right now increasingly hostile towards
India. Whether it is Facebook,
whether it is Instagram, whether it is
Google, whether it is YouTube, whether
it's X, whatever, all these are foreign
platforms.
And we depend on these platforms for
communication with each other. If the
platforms disappear, we will be all
separate from each other. We will have
no means of communicating. Right now, we
Indians take this for granted that we
can communicate with each other in real
time. I can instantaneously communicate
with somebody who's living in Shilong or
someone who's living in Gujhati or
someone who's living in Kochi or someone
who's living in Lei
and I can talk to all these people at
the same time if I want to. We all can
do it. Social media has brought India
together for the first time in a
thousand years. But it's a borrowed
platform.
It's a foreign platform
and they decide what happens on these
platforms.
For three, four years around 5 years, my
Twitter was frozen at 64,000 followers.
Yeah. Do you know that? And right now,
do you have any idea what's happening to
my YouTube? So, this is what happens
when you we have a reliance on foreign
platforms. So, that is obviously an
enemy for the country, our reliance on
other countries. So we have to become
entirely sovereign including
technological sovereignty. It's very
important. So if the prime minister has
said this, Mr. Modi has said this, I am
very hopeful that some real
transformation will come about as a
consequence of what he has said. I am
very hopeful.
YouTube is saying through there are
YouTube channels created in 2022 that
makes videos every week on how Russia is
collapsing and then it's indigenous
republics want to secede what's your
opinion you know in 2022 they were
saying that Putin has got 3 months to
live he is suffering from advanced
cancer
then they were saying that more than a
million Russian soldiers have died in 6
weeks in 6 months they were saying
Russia is about to collapse Russia is
about to lose the Ukraine war Ukraine is
winning Ukraine is winning this Ukraine
is winning that Ukraine is going to wipe
Russia out of Bahmut. Russ Ukraine is
going to do this. Every every day they
come up with a new story that Russia is
on the brink of defeat in Ukraine. Well,
and I was the one who was saying Russia
is winning and people used to make fun
of me. Where are we today?
Where are we today? Tell me. Is Ukraine
still winning? Is Russia still on on the
verge of collapse? Is Putin still about
to die from from advanced cancer?
What? What? How long will you continue
these lies?
So all of this is nonsense. It's it's
propaganda. That's my opinion and it's a
fact. By the way,
MK says, would the deep state be pro or
anti-secn amendment? If there is regime
change in India by US, then what are the
chances of the present regime come back
later through elections? If there is a
regime change in India through the US,
the presentation will never come back.
Never elections. Haha. What is what is
that vote? That's that's when vote story
will happen. Now, what is a second
amendment? I am not an expert on
American things and all that. Let me see
what is the second amendment. What is
this?
Let's let's put Google on the screen.
Let's let's Google the second amendment.
See, I am aware of all these things, but
I don't recollect things on demand
because there's way too much information
in my head. So let's see second
amendment. Second amendment
of constitution.
Okay. What is that? The second amendment
is the second amendment of the US. Oh
the right to right of the people to keep
and bear arms
and the No, we're talking about the US
uh constitution, not the Indian
constitution. Uh would the deep state be
pro or anti- US second amendment? I
think there will not
be anti-second amendment because that
will create anarchy. The people will
resist and there's going to be civil war
if you try to take away their weapons in
the US. Weapons, guns and Americans,
it's a old it's an age-old
romance,
Americans and their guns. You can't take
guns away from Americans. They're going
to they're going to put their lives on
the line. They will defend their liberty
with their lives. Do not tread on me.
The rattlesnake. So um if they try to
take the guns away there's going to be
chaos and anarchy in the US and a lot of
violence.
Barata says the way Trump's behaving it
makes it weirdly makes one agree with
the global left lunatics on how he is
actually one himself and dangerously
unstable and unpredictable even on the
issues that need no fixing.
There is a method to Trump's madness.
There is a reason why he has been given
uh the presidency of the US.
Um
see I said this last year before the
elections happened in the US
presidential elections. I said this that
I said that
it was highly unlikely that Trump will
win. But if Trump does win it will mean
that he has kissed the ring which means
that he has aligned himself with the
deep state. Now whatever he's doing it
may look like lunacy.
I mean look at the way he's behaving
with India. He has permanently lost the
trust of India. Even after Trump is gone
and there's some other US president,
India won't trust the US.
So does it is it like lunatic behavior?
Is it crazy behavior? No. The US is now
actively going to contain India. Whoever
is the president because India is now
showing the signs and symptoms of rising
as a global power. India has never shown
this before. From 1947 until 2014, India
never showed any sign of rising of of
having the ambition to rise as a global
power. Not even in 1974 when we
detonated a nuclear weapon. Not even in
1998 when we detonated five nuclear
weapons. Even then we had no ambition.
We're a we were a mediocre nation with
zero ambition of any greatness.
But from 2014 until now, India is
becoming dangerous. So what Trump is
doing makes sense from an American
perspective.
If he has set fire to the global
economic order, that also makes sense
from an American perspective. The
American perspective is that we created
an order. We created a global economic
order that our enemies have exploited to
to enrich themselves and make make
themselves powerful. So we're going to
dismantle the global order that we
created and we're going to create a new
order. So whatever he does he's doing it
may look like lunacy but it makes
eminent sense logically
from a strategic perspective.
So yeah he has this peculiarities and
all that. His behavior is kind of weird.
Um he is unlike any US president ever.
He
expects a lot of deference and all that.
He wants to be treated like an emperor.
All all those idiosyncrasies he has but
overall whatever actions he's taking are
exactly in synchronicity with what the
deep state wants. So nothing lunatic
about that.
Galler says someone's metaphor I convey.
The Anglo-Saxon can't hear a syllable
you utter not until the first rumble
from that caldera under its feet.
wishful maybe but inquisitive still
transfer the rumble and caldera to
geopolitics. So calera means the the the
the mouth of a volcano
right the crater
that is the vent of a volcano. Rumble is
the the warning that comes from volcano
before the earthquake or the before the
eruption. That's what you're talking
about. So the Anglo-Saxon can't hear a
syllable you utter not until the first
rumble from the caldera under its feet
wishful maybe but inquisitive still
what are you trying to convey is the
question so the Anglo-Saxon doesn't care
what you say blah blah blah talk talk
until you act and until the act your
actions have an actual consequences and
they can start feeling the rumbles of
the actions which means that you you are
no longer just talking you are taking
action and that and those actions will
have some actual real world consequences
That's when they start listening to you
and paying attention to you. And then
they can categorize you as potentially
dangerous, potentially to be silenced or
potentially to be eliminated or dealt
with. Maybe that's what you're talking
about in geopolitics. And when you when
I say you, it means nations.
So as long as India was preaching to the
world blah blah, om shanti, nonviolence,
etc., no one cared. No one cared. But
now India is actually transforming
itself economically and that is
sending rumbles across the world and so
on. So now they are paying attention to
India and taking action against India.
Right. Mera says was the student
uprising in Gujarati hostel in Indra
Gandhi tenor led by JP Narayan a
prologue or trial run for future student
revolution. I have absolutely no idea
about this Gujarat
hostel.
I don't know. I'm I'm very sorry. And
this is like Indian history we're
talking about here. But I'm discussing
geopolitics ma'am over here. Uh so even
if I had the answer to the question, I
would I I'm not taking geo history
questions today. Uh we're discussing
only geopolitics. I said that in the
beginning and and even the title of this
live stream is geopolitics. So um and
anyway, I am not aware of this. There
was a student uprising in a Gujarati
hostel during Indra Gandhi's time led by
JP Narayan.
Now I'm not familiar with that part of
history. Sorry. Very sorry.
Okay. AKS Baga says, "Why don't you
start a company to advise corporations
on on current affairs and geopolitics
just like the Eurasia group or Peter
Zaham?" Well, that's an idea that will
make me even more dangerous than I am
right now and even more inconvenient
than I am right now.
Do Indian corporations need this?
I mean they need this but are they aware
of the fact that they need this the need
for geopolitical forecasting in risk
analysis?
Oh, it's a it's an idea. It's a good
idea you're giving here. Maybe I shall
think about it seriously. Thank you for
the idea.
Maybe I may have thought of the idea
actually, you know. Who knows? Rahul
Lakshman says, "Maybe Starlink will be
our link to the America Party long-term
international relations. Perhaps
Starlink needs to be removed from India.
It is our link to nothing but
Vasalhood." Okay. Uh, no America, no
long-term international relations.
Starlink is poison. Starlink is
dangerous for India.
It will empower anti-India elements.
Nothing. There's no free gift in the
world. There's no free service in the
world. Even if the service is a paid
service, still it has nefarious
purposes. Starlink needs to be removed
from India. It should never be
operationalized in India. That is my
sincere advice to the government of
India.
Divor Singh says, "I personally did not
face any racism here in the US. In fact,
the US right-wing people liked me. But
is it good for Americans if H-1B visa
holders go back?
Is it good for Americans? Okay, I'm glad
you did not face any racism. That's
good. Right-wing people lie to you.
Well, I'm glad to hear that. Fine. Okay.
Now, is it good for the US if H-1B visa
holders go back? I mean, what percentage
of American job openings
do H-1B visa holders even take? I must
I'm just guessing out here but I'm
guessing it's about 2 3%.
So of let's say you have a 100
hypothetically 100 job openings in the
US most likely only two or three of the
job openings openings will actually go
to H1B visa holders. So that's a
minuscule percentage first of all but
what kind of jobs do H1B visa holders
do? Generally they do extremely
important jobs. They are generally
involved in in technical operations in
the uh in generally typically in the
field of IT. Uh they handle the IT
operations for most Fortune 500
companies. Uh they are behind the work
for they are a significant component of
the workforce in Silicon Valley and
various American tech corporations and
startups. So even though the number of
jobs is a small percentage of the
overall US job market, even even then
the kind of work they're doing is
critical for for for
the US. So if you send these people
back, obviously you're going to replace
them with Americans, but then the
expenditure shoots up, right? So, I am
expecting that the H-1B visa holders,
they'll be phased out gradually in a way
that it's not going to cause any shocks
to American fortune 500 companies or
startups or or tech giants. Um,
so I don't think the H1B visa holders
are going to going to be evicted
overnight. If they are evicted
gradually, it will happen slowly. It'll
be a slow process. Uh the fact that
you're going to have to pay $100,000 for
each H1B visa application going forward
itself tells you that H1B visa holder I
mean H1 there's going to be way fewer
H1B visa applications that will come in
in the first place. uh so overall they
are slowly phasing this this visa out
and it's it should the objective is to
target Indians mainly because Indians
make up about 70% of the H-1B visa uh
applications and and the H1B visa
holders who are currently in the US um
so if if if the H1B visa holders go back
overnight it's going to be catastrophic
for the US but if they are phased out
gradually as will most likely happen
then the US will be able to adjust and
and uh yeah things will become more
expensive for the fortune 500 companies
and most likely those jobs will will be
offshored.
So let's say let's say you are a US
company and you have let's say a
thousand for example H1B visa folks who
work for you. Now it's going to be super
expensive to renew those visas and so
on. So if I was running that that
company I would simply offshore those
jobs to Bangalore or Hyderabad or
somewhere. So I'll start a branch of my
company in Bangalore or Hyderabad. I'll
hire a thousand Indian IT personnel
there at higher rates than what Indians
generally expect but way lower than what
American workers have to be paid. So
it's a win-win for me. That's that's
most likely what will happen.
YouTube says, "Is there any Russian
lobby in Israel like Israeli lobby in
the US?" Not that I'm aware of. I don't
I'm not aware of any.
Dan Dave says really is not
reality is not enough Americans for STEM
jobs in the US. Most most STEM courses
in universities have 90% plus
international students. Yes. Very few
Americans. They got to be okay with jobs
being outsourced I guess. Yeah. The
reality is if you go to any STEM if you
go to any major American university or
even non- major US university even if
it's a university that's not in the top
100 in the US and you go to their STEM
departments you know physics or
chemistry or or biotechnology or
whatever a significant portion of the
students are non-Americans lots of
Indians everywhere you go to any
American university or college campus
you'll see Indians all over the place
Indian kids Indian students Um, so
you're right. Most STEM courses in in
universities have 90% plus international
students, very few Americans. So, so
even if you get rid of the H-1B visa
holders, where are you going to find the
the Americans who will take over in
those in those STEM jobs? That's the
question. So then the alternative is to
outsource the jobs. That's the only
alternative that remains until you
revamp your education system and bring
in more Americans uh who go through the
STEM courses which which is going to
take years if not decades even even and
that to assuming that they they start
the the overhole of the education system
and and stop bringing in foreigners and
and push more Americans into that. So
the only alternative is to outsource the
jobs which means that the American
companies instead of bringing in H1B
visa holders are going to outsource the
jobs to places like like Hyderabad or or
Bangalore or maybe Manila or or wherever
else right and they're going to have
people working there
and that's what so so the if you if the
objective is to have more jobs uh being
taken over by Americans well it's not
going to happen right? So they have
they're going to have no option but to
outsource the jobs and yeah I agree with
you about this. Uh Divor says is
genocide inherently bad through what
line of morality do we get that if India
did what Israel is doing right now will
Dharmx be okay with it?
So are you saying Israel is doing a
genocide right now? Uh I am not aware of
what's happening in in Gaza or whatever.
Some people are saying that Israel is
conducting genocide. I don't know. Uh
there are conflicting reports that come
out of the place. The Israelis are
saying that we are simply defending our
nation and the Palestinians are are
terrorists and we've got to kill the
terrorists and if there is some
collateral damage then sad is said. Um
and and what's the definition of
genocide? Is it like a thousand people?
Is it 10,000 people? Is it 50,000
people? Is it 100,000 people? Is it a
million? Where does the line start?
There's no definition. Anyone can call
anything genocide. But now the question
you're asking is, is genocide inherently
inherently bad?
Well,
are we going into the realms of moral
relativism here? That's a philosophical
concept.
Is are some genocides good and are some
evil? I mean, is that is it like that? I
think we have to take a clear stand that
killing people is evil. But then the
question is
all people aren't the same. Some people
are terrorists. What are you going to do
with them? So I'm not sure what line of
I would say killing unarmed people is
wrong. Killing civilians is wrong. But
what if those civilians are harboring
terrorists? In that case I would say you
reclassify the civilians as active
combatants if they are harboring
terrorists and empowering terrorists. So
in that case is Israel really doing
something bad. I mean after all the they
did implement the two-state solution the
Israelis by giving over self self-
administration rights and privileges to
the people of Gaza but what did the
people of Gaza do with that with that
freedom the Israelis gave them they
elected Hamas and empowered Hamas and
launched all kinds of attacks on Israel
as a consequence because they want the
land to be free from the from the river
to the sea which means that they believe
Israel has no right to exist. Israel
says, "We're going to exist. Deal with
it, and if you're going to resist us,
we're going to do whatever it takes."
So, who's right? Who's wrong here? I
would say Israel has the right to defend
itself. I would say that what happened
in 2023 was a terrorist attack, a
heinous, barbaric terrorist attack. But
the Palestinians will say that the
Israelis have been oppressing us for so
long that we had no option. So, I don't
know where's the right, where's the
wrong. The world is complicated. There's
no black and white in the world. It's
all shades of gray. I would say that
what's your morality depends on who you
are. Everybody is going to have a
different definition of morality.
Yeah. Some people will say genocide is
good. Some some people will say that.
Some cultures will say that genocide is
okay as long as we are killing people
who are not part of our religion or
culture. Some religions and cultures
believe in that. Right? I mean the
Anglo-Saxons genocided the Native
Americans. They said that the genocide
was good. They were barbarians. They
were fighting all the time. So we killed
them off. and this is our land now.
Maybe that genocide is bad is is good
from their perspective. I don't know. If
India did what Israel is doing right
now, will Dharmics be okay with it? Um
I'm not sure what is the ter definition
of Dharmics? Is anyone who has a birth
certificate that says Hindu is that
person is are all those people dharmic?
Most of those people have no connection
with dharma anymore. They are
dassinated.
They have no connection. They don't even
know what Dharmic philosophy is. Right?
So I think dharmic would actually mean
the people who actually understand what
dharma is and that's very few Indians
today. Will they be okay with it? I
think dharma says that you have the
right to defend yourself and you have to
the right to to def to destroy a dharma.
So dharmics will be okay with it if they
actually understand dharma. But the
people who are Hindu nominally in name
they may be against it.
It's very possible. Say yeah.
Vivik Singh says got to know that H
closed the Sukoy MKI assembly line in
2018 itself. What's wrong with the
babos? It could have helped today in
managing our strength. That's why the
country cannot be run by babus.
And the question also arises that how
can babus take the decision bureaucrats
and was the government not aware of
this? See, I I I don't delve into these
matters and I don't know what the hell
is happening. Did HL close the Sukoy?
Let let's let's fact check this. Okay.
Uh H A L S U
30 MKI
Assembly
closed
2018.
Um no did not close in 2018. HL was
building in 2018
while a decision. So this is Swaraj mag
that more orders might might be in the
pipeline and so on.
Closed or not?
Is the assembly line closed or not?
No, it's not closed. They won a contract
in late 2024 to produce 12 new Sukoy MKI
aircraft under license and HL has
proposed submitted proposals for
resuming production etc. HL's Nashik
division also continues to repair and
overhaul the SU30s in service.
And here it says HL will take 24 months
to restart.
The Nashik factory has been shut for 12
24 months.
So we're getting conflicting so
information over here. I'm not sure what
the truth is. I I cannot comment right
now. It'll take me some more time to do
a proper facteing. But it looks like
there could be issues and these issues
typically are
potentially hypothetically caused by
bureaucrats. So yeah, bureaucrats need
to be held in tight tight leash by the
government of India. That's very
important. Bureaucrats their only job is
to carry out instructions, not to become
decision makers as such. Right?
Uh says USA is bullying you. Why don't
India ask me for help? Because you see
they are bullying you even more.
I'm sorry to say sir, they are bullying
you even more.
They have imposed a million sanctions on
you for the past 20 30 years. Uh Israel
just bombarded you and hammered you
unfortunately
and the Americans obviously were
perfectly happy with that. The Americans
have tried their best to freeze your
nuclear uh enrichment program.
Donald Trump bombed your nuclear nuclear
enrichment program recently a few weeks
ago. Right? So you are being bullied way
worse than us.
Right? You are at the receiving end very
badly
and you are considerably less powerful
than us. So with the the highest of
respect, why would we ask you for help,
sir? Right. Why would we ask you for
help? Logically. Okay. Pushan says, "Was
Nvidia likely bullied in buying a stake
in Intel?" I have no idea. Can't answer
the question. I haven't looked into
this. Sorry.
Balra Singh, thank you very much sir.
Thank you sir. Okay. DVN Singh says
LGBTQ is used as a geopolitical tool
sometimes but but mostly internal
politics. Did LGBTQ exist in ancient
India?
How should we think about it? Look
LGBTQ is indeed a thing. No I mean what
is LGBTQ? First of all, lesbian
uh gay, bi-gender, no bisexual,
transgender and queer.
So that is that
in ancient Indian India there would have
been some um homosexual people. I
suppose I've seen some one or two
carvings of some homosexual acts
somewhere, you know. So clearly it did
exist in India and you will
sadly for the liberals you will find not
a single text in India's enormous
literary realm
where there is a single reference to any
kind of demonization of of of homosexual
people. Nothing at all. And there is no
mention of homosexual people or
homosexuality that I know of. So clearly
homosexuality did exist and
nobody did anything about it. It was
allowed to exist. India has always
always had this culture live and let
live. As long as you are not interfering
in my life and as long as you're not
causing any harm to society, you you
live your life. You do you do you. We
don't care. That's always been India's
approach. And you will not find a single
text anywhere in India that that has any
kind of demonization of of uh homosexual
people. Now, LGBTQ, lesbian, gay,
transgender, blah, blah, blah. I'm not
sure of all that all of that spectrum
business happened in India. I'm not sure
about that. Um, it probably did exist in
India. Homosexuality at least. How
should we think about it? We should
think about it as something that existed
that we didn't care about. We did not
glorify it or exalt it. We did not
mention it, which means it would have
been some kind of fringe thing in the
society. and uh it it existed and we
didn't care about it. That's it. So no
oppression and and no glorification. We
simply it must have been regarded as
some kind of fringe behavior and let it
be. Let them do what they're doing as
long as they don't harm society. That's
how it was.
Divor Singh says USA has bought a stake
in Intel. Does it make Intel an arm of
the US military?
Um
everything is an arm of the US military.
Google is an arm of the US military.
Alphabet is a arm of the US military.
Uh all these AI companies are arms of
the US military.
And now they've officially taken a stake
in Intel, right? Uh someone asked just
now about Nvidia. Was Nvidia bullied
into buying a stake in Intel? I'm not
aware of the Nvidia thing, but the US
has taken at least a 10% stake, right?
the US government in uh Intel 10% or or
more. I'm not I don't remember the exact
figure. So if they have officially taken
a stake, it means that Intel is now
obviously clearly an arm of the US
government and the US military and
overall all these US corporations, tech
corporations, they are de facto uh
geopolitical tools of the US. And see in
2010 when Edward Snowden leaked out that
prism program P R I SM prism
what was what he revealed is that all
the US tech firms of that time were
sharing intelligence with the US
government in real time
and uh the nations that were the most
under surveillance the at the top spot
was India in 2010.
So even if the US has not acquired
stakes in all these tech giants, they
were still sharing whatever information
the US government wanted with the US
government in real time. So even if a
stake is not acquired, the US tech
giants are still
um an extension of the US government's
geopolitical policy and military policy.
Geopolitical Dubet says, "Has the US
operationalized its hypersonic missile?
I'm not sure. I'm sure they have some
kind of hypersonic missiles.
Um, look, first of all, they they have
ICBMs and so on which are not
hypersonic. They are like they they they
their speeds are re-entry speeds. So
there is supersonic which is Mach 1,
Mach 2, there's hypersonic which is M 5,
M 6, M 7 and there's re-entry speeds
which is MK 20 plus. So the US has
re-entry speed missiles which is
ballistic missiles. Um,
do have they operationalized hypersonic
missiles? They have hypersonic missiles
under development. I don't remember the
exact names of the missiles, but uh I'm
not sure if they've operationalized
those. As far as I know that the the
fastest hypersonic missiles in existence
are the Tircon and the Kinjaw, which are
the Russian missiles
and uh eventually the Brahos 2 will
become one of those and the Brahos one
right now which we we use it's a
supersonic missile M 2, Mach 3, right?
So yeah, I'm not sure about the exact uh
status of whatever hypersonic missile
development is happening in the US.
MK says Pakistan is militarily gearing
up against India or resuming operation
Synindur now is crucial because the US
would sanction any time now or in the
future. The moment we start a war with
Pakistan or or a military operation, the
US will impose sanctions now on India or
they will take some very strong action
against India and the Americans will
over time strengthen the Pakistani
military and make it like almost as
powerful as India or at least as
powerful enough that they can withstand
an operation Synindhur like situation
and potentially cause much more harm to
India. So that's why this this uh pact
has happened between Pakistan and Saudi
Arabia. The Americans will now route
military equipment and funding through
Saudi Arabia into Pakistan. So it's it's
going to be a tough situation for India.
Um if you want to end the Pakistan
threat, I think the longer we wait, the
more dangerous and more difficult it
will become for India. So yes, I agree
with you there. AKS Baga says, "My
thoughts on the 4 billion deal to buy
the P8 Poseidon. We need to scrap that
deal. We cannot buy any American defense
equipment.
It's poison. It'll be used against us.
It can it will have back doors. It will
have kill switches and so much more. I
think it makes no sense for India to
acquire even a screwdriver from the US
anymore. So, end Starlink, end all these
programs. Whatever money has flown under
the bridge, forget about it and move on.
Ritwick says you are my second favorite
YouTuber of Tanish Rajput. Okay, thank
you sir. He said Balojasthan wanted to
join India and sign document of
accession. I said that many years ago.
Uh what but when Pakistan attacked them,
India refused to help them. Is it true?
Look this is a historical question but
yes
Balojasthan the Khan of Kalat I must
have made videos about this in 2021. The
Khan of Kalat had signed the instrument
of accession and he had sent it to Prime
Minister Neu. Mr. Neu rejected that.
Okay.
And after that, Jina ordered the
invasion of Balojasthan and Balojasthan
was annexed by Pakistan and India
refused to do a thing about it. Entirely
true. Entirely true. This is a matter of
historical record. So Kalat is was was
one of the major princely states in
Baljasthan and they wanted to have
nothing to do with Pakistan. They wanted
to join India.
Right? So it's entirely true. Yes.
Divor Singh says is an individual a unit
of society or is a family a unit of
society? If family then nuclear family
or joint family it depends on the nature
of the society and what you want to
achieve with your society.
If you look at the the philosophy of
and the the philosophy of
and s and so on they will say that the
individual is is the unit of the
society. Yes. So the western perspective
the Anglo-Saxon perspective also is such
that the individual is the unit of
society. Among the Europeans you have
different cultures. The Anglo-Saxons are
the most individualistic of the
Europeans. I do a thought experiment if
you can not a thought no do an actual
real life experiment if you can do it.
Spend some time in England and if
possible spend some time interacting
with people going to their house
spending time with their family and see
how the interactions between the family
members are. Then go to France, spend
time if you have friends, go to
someone's house and see how they
interact with their elders and children
and see the differences. Go to France,
go to Germany, go to various European
nations. You will find that in
continental Europe, the the European
people have a high regard for elders.
Not as much as people in the
subcontinent do. In the subcontinent, we
literally touch the feet of our elders.
We worship our elders like literal gods
right in India especially parents and
grandparents and so on or family elders
in Europe there is still some vestige of
that people still treat elders with with
respect and and defer to elders in
England in the Anglo-Saxon world they
treat elders like rubbish
they call them by their first name and
they they'll make fun of them they mock
their elders right so in So there's
there's differences in society and you
will realize this if you spend time in
these societies. So in Europe which is
now dominated by the Anglo-Saxons and
their their their worldview the
individual is the unit of society. In
the Europe in the US also the individual
is regarded as the unit of society. Um
and you will see Vak Ramaswami saying
that the nuclear family is the greatest
thing that the west has done and all.
um historically in Asia in Asian
cultures I'm not just talking about
dharmic cultures even confusion culture
and all the family and not just the
family but the extended family was the
was the unit of society that's a more
cohesive society right so it depends on
the culture it depends on the
civilization if it's a civilization
India China Japan we are civilizations
the west whatever it is they call
themselves western civilization but they
regard the individual as the unit of
society in India historically ally the
extended family was the unit of society
and also in China also in various Asian
cultures. So it depends on the context
the milu the social social and
civilizational con context if there is
one
anonymous scientist says Israel has
developed a laser iron beam defense
system. Should India talk to Israel for
getting such systems? It can take out
cheap packed drones. We have also
developed
a laser based uh okay directed energy
weapons right let's let's let's look
into this we have developed one too uh
India directed India India directed
energy weapon there was news recently uh
the MK2A 30 kowatt laser based directed
energy weapon capable of neutralizing
drones and surveillance sensors
developed by DRDO the system can disable
aerial threats ranges over 3 km which is
like the jeepack drones uh by cutting
through through targets with a powerful
laser beam. India is now one of the few
countries globally with this advanced
anti- drone technology with plans for
more powerful 50 to 100 kowatt variants
and potential future satellite and
maritime applications.
So I don't think we see Israel is our
wonderful partner and friend and uh we
have developed uh jointly developed
systems like the Barak missile and and
so on. We are also uh manufacturing
Israeli designed Harop drones in India.
The Adani uh the Adani um
um company is is doing that and so on.
But we have directed energy weapons. So
let's let's compare that with the
Israeli laser iron
uh you know iron defense. So Israel
Israel Israel
Israel
laser laser I
laser iron beam
kilo. Let's see. It's a 100 kilowatt
laser uh laser that is part of the ironb
iron thing whatever they have. Then we
currently have a 30 kow system. Okay.
Amp it up to 100 kow.
Once you have an operational 30 kow
system, it's not going to be that
difficult now to amp it up to 100 kow.
You've already done the hard work by
developing the system. Now all you have
to do is make it is make it more
powerful. So I don't think we need to um
seek Israeli help in this matter. Israel
is definitely a nation with whom we have
a tremendous amount of strategic
convergence and and synergy and there's
so much potential in the India Israel
relationship. But in this matter we are
not lacking in technology. So we're
going to be able to do it on our own.
Okay. AKS BA says did the US hide
heroh's war crimes in China, Korea, etc.
Was Hirohito really in charge of things?
You have to ask yourselves this. Why was
Hirohito not executed?
Why was he allowed to stay on? H
this goes back to the major restoration.
The major restoration was this
tremendous transformation of Japanese
society and governance.
They destroyed the old samurai system.
They killed off the samurai,
the traditional guardians of Japan, the
vegetarian
fish eating,
beef abhoring
defenders of Japan, the Buddhist, Hindu
Buddhist, they say Buddhist, but they
they incorporated lots of elements of
Hinduism. The the samurai, they tried to
portray Hinduism as a foreign religion.
And the the the major restoration was a
coup against the emperor.
So you had a 16-year-old or or teenage
emperor who was then propped up as a
puppet as a figurehead. But the real
power lay in the hands of the ministers
and they transformed Japan into an into
an imperial hegemonic expansionist
power, a non-harmic power. They made the
emperor eat beef in public to make the
whole of Japan beef eating, right? And
they did the war crimes eventually in
Korea, Japan, in Korea, China, etc.
Hirohito was helpless. He was just a
mere figurehead, a puppet.
You understand? Now the Americans knew
what the Japanese military had done.
unit 3, what 230 or whatever the hell it
was, they did all kinds of horrific
medical experimentation.
Why didn't the US
publicized this very much? Why?
Because the Americans made a deal with
the Japanese military. You give us all
your medical records that you have
obtained as as part of this horrific
human experimentation. Give us all the
records. We'll let you go scot-free.
No trial, no no no no no punishment,
nothing. So the Japanese had done all
kinds of horrific experiments. How long
can a human be human being be kept alive
in freezing water? What if the
temperature is 4°? How long can a human
survive? You take 10 subjects, put them
in freezing water, 4° centigrade, and
let's see how long it takes on average
for their hearts to stop beating. Then
do the same experiment with with 0°
instead of 4°. then do it at -5°.
That sort of horrific experimentation
they did to see how long humans can
survive cold water exposure at various
temperatures. Very valuable information
that the Americans took from the
Japanese and in exchange for that they
did not publicize these war crimes of
the Japanese Imperial Army. Hirohito
probably did not did not even know half
the things that happened. the things
that the Japanese military did in in
Nanjing.
The first time I saw I found out about
naning, I think I I'm sure I do not eat
for a couple of days. That's how
horrific it was. Today, we are all
immune to these horrific images that are
are all around the internet. But the
first time you see such a thing, it's
like gh. So, we Americans benefited from
this. They hate all these war crimes.
Oh, wow. We have reached two hours.
Please stop taking super chats. I need
to end this now. soon as soon as
possible whatever super chats exist I
will obviously go through those but
please don't take any more super chats
thank you very much so says not a
geopolitical question
please comment on Dr. Uni Krishnan from
TF TF are experimentally disproving
Einstein's special relativity.
I haven't seen this news. I don't
believe it. Einstein's
special relative. Who cares about
special relativity? Try and disprove
general relativity.
People have been trying to disprove
general relativity since 1915.
Thousands of attempts have been made. If
general relativity did not work, your
GPS would not work.
Do you know why why why things fall?
Why why do you have weight?
Why do you weigh 70 kilos or whatever it
is that you weigh? It's because of the
curvature
not of space but of time.
Mass curve is not just space but time.
according to the Einstein field
equations the temporal curvature is more
than the the the spatial curvature and
that's what was used in GPS satellites
and GPS satellites perform precisely as
per the equations the field equations of
Einstein so all these stories of someone
disproving general relativity or special
relativity I don't believe it
because I I have studied all this I
understand how it works I don't believe
Yes. Anyway, not a geopolitical
question. Prashant says, "Time for AI
minister like Albania for transparency."
All right, sir. I will ask the
government to consider that, sir. Thank
you for the suggestion.
Uh MK says, "Great powers vosalize or
conquer neighboring states and political
rivals or potential rivals. Given that
Europe satisfies satisfies both, why
didn't the British Empire attempt to do
so? Great powers vaselize conquer
neighboring states and potential rivals.
Given that Europe satisfies both Europe
was not that easy to conquer. The French
were powerful enough. The French nearly
wiped out the whole of Europe. Napoleon.
Um
so the deal was that we will conquer
non-white races. It all starts with the
treaty of Toresiat.
The treaty of Tores.
It it divided the world into two halves
between Spain and Portugal, but not the
white nations, the non-white nations,
the non-Christian nations. Those were to
be colonized and vasalized.
Right? So eventually Britain became a
major power much more than Spain or
Portugal and the Treaty of Thoras went
out of the window and Britain said, "I
don't care if it's east or west. I'll
conquer everybody." But it was only
going to target non-Christian, non-white
countries.
Uh and of course in Europe you had other
issues because Europe also was a
technological advance and not that easy
to conquer. It's a very good question.
You're asking very interesting question
as to why did Britain only conquer let's
say uh Egypt and Africa and and the
crown jewel was India and uh settle
Australia after genociding the natives
and so on. And why not do the same in
Europe?
Yeah. because of multiple reasons,
multiple reasons, complicated reasons.
First of all, these are all white
countries. You don't do the same thing
that you do the to non-whites to white
people. Secondly, they were Europe was
still definitely a capable of of
defending itself, right? Across the
English Channel of France. France was a
formidable opponent, right? But France
did not have the
what's the polite term? did not have the
the the the jean quality that the
British have of conquering far away
lands. The British understood power. The
French did the French the way the French
did not. How to conquer and colonize
non-whites. The French were not that
good. The British were far better. But
the British were not capable of
conquering and colonizing the French.
Otherwise, it would lead to another
100red-year war or whatever. So, yeah.
Divor Singh says why would America let
its nuclear warheads fall in numbers
against Russia? I think they still have
their 2,000 the 25,000 and just lie.
Entirely possible.
These numbers that are put out in the
public domain h that the US has 5,100
let's say and Russia has 5,800 nuclear
warheads and China has 650 and France
has 250 and India has 170 and Pakistan
has 165. How on earth does the western
media know these numbers? They went and
asked Mr. Putin. Mr. Putin, how many do
you have? Yes. See, I have six 5,800.
Yes. Thank you. You going to believe
that? Why would anyone diverge the real
numbers? They went to Mr. Modi sir, how
much do I have?
170.
I mean, really, will Mr. Modi say that?
How do they know how many nukes we have
or Pakistan has? These are numbers that
pull out of god knows where. So it's
entirely possible that the US may have
25,000 and are lying. I completely agree
with you sir.
Dark knight says please explain the
implications of the Saudi Pakistan
alliance. Is it another geopolitical
disaster for India? I may be a little
too harsh. I'll tell you what it is.
Let's say you are the overlord of the
world and you have some neighbor some
nations who are still not under your
control. naughty nations. So what do you
do? You want to contain those nations.
China is a bad nation. Not under US
control. Russia very naughty. Not under
US control. India
not even half as powerful as China but
still being remaining independent. Let's
deal with India first. Then we'll deal
with the others. So what do you do to
deal with India? You prop up Pakistan.
But Pakistan got hammered by India in
operation zindu 3 days. Visibly
hammered. You saw all those missiles
falling in and and hammering various air
bases and whatnot, right? It it all came
out on social media. You can't hide that
Pakistan got hammered. What do you do
then? You want to prop up Pakistan. You
want to send them funds. You want to
send them military equipment. So, so you
talk to a different vasal of your Saudi
Arabia. You tell them you are going to
be the conduit for military equipment
into Pakistan. Oh, if I directly send
arms and funds to Pakistan, my public
will ask me this is a terrorist nation
who who harbored Osama bin Laden. So why
is Donald Trump doing this? This is not
why we voted for you. So Trump will then
silently route it through Saudi Arabia
and then you can blame Saudi Arabia if
something goes wrong.
So that's the implication. The
implication is that the US is going to
prop up Pakistan is going to strengthen
Pakistan is going to supply Pakistan
with funds and military equipment to
make it as powerful as India. So that
next time there is operation Pakistan
may actually ostentially win this may
take two three years to happen but let's
say in two three years Pakistan may be
made as powerful as India militarily in
a from a conventional perspective that's
the objective is it a disaster for India
it is potentially disaster for India it
doesn't mean that Saudi Arabia will
fight against India if there's a war
with Pakistan no Saudi Arabia will stay
out but they will be the conduit through
which all this funding and all this
military equipment is routed into
Pakistan
So the US is essentially playing this
game. They have this policy of
containing India through encirclement.
That is the deal.
And why is it happening? It's because
India matters now. Since 1947 until now,
India has not mattered. But now India is
India matters. So that's why this is the
situation. Anonymous scientist says the
US vasals UK, Canada and Australia have
recognized Palestine. Is it a message to
Trump or something else? They will not
dare go against Trump. Maybe Trump
himself has said that you guys can go
ahead and do this so that we can play
both sides of the game. Yeah, we I will
have three of my vasals recognize
Palestine, but I will recogn I will I
will support Israel. So So this
recognition is just words. Okay, it's
nominal recognition. We hereby recognize
Palestine, a nation that doesn't exist.
But will the UK, Canada, and Australia
actually fund the Palestinian movement?
Will they supply weapons to them against
Israel? They will not dare do such a
thing. This is just words. Like I keep
saying, like I keep saying over and over
again, hundreds of millions of times,
words and actions. Focus on the actions.
Ignore the words. I don't care about the
words. Yeah.
Kajuru Thornne says, "What can the
government of India do to extract
maximum advantage from N's force to
return if their skills and capital are
not channeled? I fear they may they will
become disgruntled, ready and willing
Western agents.
If you want to extract maximum advantage
from NRIs who are potentially forced to
return, you have to give them the same
opportunities they sought when they
escaped India." Why did they leave
India? Because India did not give them
the living standards they aspire for.
They left India because they got far
better opportunities to to flourish to
explore their full potential,
professional potential outside of India.
India doesn't give you that. You don't
get good living stands in India. You get
all kinds of alleged corruption issues
in India. There is no meritocracy in
India. You don't get the job
opportunities that you go go get outside
in India. you don't you don't get the
same salaries in India that you get
outside of the outside of India in the
US if you want to extract the maximum
advantage you have to give them what
they were getting in the US
otherwise they will not come back to
India they'll go somewhere else they'll
go to Singapore they'll go to Australia
they'll go to China they'll go to Russia
they'll go to Germany they'll go to
France they'll go to Italy they'll go
somewhere else they'll go to the UK
they'll go anywhere but come back to
India and if they're forced to come back
to India and they don't get those
opportunities they're not going to be
happy in India they're going to be very
sad very very depressed people and you
don't want people like that. You want
people to be happy. You want talented
people to be happy and in the right
position in India. So that's what needs
to happen otherwise. Yeah. Then we are
wasting another opportunity.
Project smiling Buddha says happy
Navaratri to you and to everybody else.
Happy Navatri to you sir and to
everybody else as well. Happy Navatri.
Thank you. Dur Singh says are some races
and societies superior to others? Yes is
all I'll say.
Go says why can't the US make its
permanent ally make India its permanent
ally to counter China and Russia? Why
can't they understand that India is a
peaceloving country and won't fight the
US even if it gets powerful? So what
you're saying is let's let's deconstruct
the logic. India is a peaceloving
country. India won't fight the US even
if India becomes powerful. So India
should become an American permanent ally
to counter China and Russia. Then the US
will say you fight China and Russia and
we'll fight.
But aren't we a peace-loving country?
Then why should we fight someone's war?
Why
don't we have any pride or self-respect?
Or do we want to once again go down the
East India Company road and become
someone's facal?
I want India to be no one's permanent
ally.
I want India to remain sovereign.
And whoever deals with us in a
respectful mutually beneficial manner,
we shall have dealings, mutually
beneficial dealings with them. We will
be no one's vasal.
You become someone's vasal.
You are using the word ally. But when
the Americans talk about allies, they're
talking about vasals. Okay, understand
that when the US uses the term ally,
they are only referring to their vasals
and we will be nobody's vasal.
So it doesn't work like that.
The US can't make India its permanent
vasal because we are unwilling to be
anyone's vasal.
Uh Dn Singh says UK royal family are
Germans and not British to a significant
extent. Yes. Right.
Um see all the European royal families
are interrelated.
If you see uh the last what was it the
the the German the king of Germany
before the first world war what's his
name the Kaiser Wilhelm
um let's let's Google that
uh Kaiser
um the king of Prussia
uh what's he look like
who was who was his predecessor So I
don't remember exactly who it was, but
you see the the king of England, he had
this great resemblance to the king of
Germany of the time. I forget which one
was which and I'll not go and go and
Google that and do the research. But uh
these families are all all
interconnected. For example, the mount
battens, right? They are nobility. They
are aristocracy. They're not royalty.
But the mount batns are actually the
battenburggs.
Battenburggs.
But during the first world war when
Germany became the enemy, they changed
their name from Batenburgg to Mount
Batton. So many of these people are are
of German origin ancestry. Iksbaga says,
is it a policy of the US to have less
nukes than Russia? Well, they claim to
have a policy of having less nukes than
Russia. They currently officially have
less nukes than Russia, but who knows
what the truth is. Maybe they have 10
times the nukes that Russia has. It's
possible, right?
I mean, why would you have a policy of
being less weak than somebody when you
have the ability to be more powerful?
It's possible that they may secretly
have more nukes than Russia, but they're
just claiming to have less nukes. So, we
don't know. Maybe they have more.
Divining says, "The Westerners say that
the tallest building in South Africa
before the British came was built by
termites, not humans. Were they that
backwards? I have no idea." See, what
happened in Africa is is is a tragedy.
Not a tragedy. It's it's a horror.
Africa was devastated by by the
Europeans. There was this scramble for
Africa in the 19th century. Before that
the European explorers like Dr.
Livingston and and Stanley and or
whoever they they through a lot of
personal hardship they went went and
explored various parts of Africa and
eventually you had people like Cecil
Roads and and various other people who
started the process of colonizing
Africa. Southern Africa was colonized
and eventually the Belgians colonized
Africa. The Germans genocided some
people in Western Africa. The French got
into Africa. The English were all over
the place and they destroyed Africa.
And then the historians wrote that the
Africans were a bunch of barbarians who
were cannibals and bloodthirsty people
and human sacrifice. So it made sense to
destroy those kingdoms, right?
But how can we trust the records, the
historical claims of the people who
destroyed Africa and then used history
to justify the destruction? Maybe the
Africans were super civilized, but just
just not as dangerous as the whites
were. They were maybe not as skilled in
in genocide and massacres and violence
as the as the Europeans were. So the
Europeans did that and then they wrote
history that the Africans were they they
engaged in mindless human sacrifice and
all kinds of human torture and they
they're cannibals and so on. So that's
why we had to civilize them. So I don't
trust any of these European histories.
The same way I don't trust the European
histories of the of the Americas
today,
especially the the the the right-wing
Americans, they justify their occupation
of the land by claiming that the native
Americans were barbarians. They were
extremely cruel towards each other. They
were in a perpetual state of warfare
with each other. They never built
anything of any value, which is why we
had to we had to civilize them and we
had to take over the land and then
uplift them. So you know you can always
use these justifications to to paper
over what you have done which is
genocide. So I don't know whether the
Africans were I don't know if the
Africans were that that backward the way
the Europeans claim. Uh if you go to
places like Zimbabwe for example, you
will find the remnants of ancient large
buildings that look like castles. Uh the
kingdom of Zimbabwe for example. Um
it looks like Africa had
you know culture and history and today
Africa if you go there the people look
like they are totally univilized they
have no way no understanding of how to
how to
you know how to govern a civilized
society maybe because it's of it's a
it's because of couple of centuries of
abject poverty and complete dassination
who knows
Divor Singh says What was all that
bohemian gloves grove stuff? Bill
Clinton, Obama all went there. Some guys
did a sting operation found many many
powerful people go there. This is all
about the deep state and so on. I don't
know really about much about this. Um
some place called Bohemian Grove where
weird rituals are done allegedly and
allegedly the most powerful people in
the country go there for a retreat. I
don't know maybe once a year. I don't
know what what what intervals or
whatever. And um maybe shady stuff
happens there. I don't know, sir. I
don't know. I've heard these rumors and
stuff. I've also seen that alleged video
that's come out of some kind of weird
fire ritual happening somewhere. I don't
know if it's Bohemian Bohemian Grove. I
don't I don't see any US president
there. I don't know. Could be could be
anything. So
the absence of evidence doesn't mean the
evidence of absence, but it doesn't mean
the other way vice versa also. So I
don't know. I've heard of I've heard
these rumors but I've not seen any
evidence any clinching evidence. So
can't say
YouTube says western media
intellects and veterans pedal the
narrative of India turning authoritarian
and fascist against under Modi. It's an
is it an excuse for supporting Pakistan
dictatorship? It's an excuse for doing
in the future a regime change operation
in India and also for supporting
Pakistan dictatorship and so on. If if
India is a fascist nation, then what's
the evidence of it? What's the evidence?
You have to show evidence of it. Right?
If you said that India is a Nazi nation,
for example, like some people claim,
where are the godamn concentration
camps? Where in the US? I can show you
the concentration camps. They're called
reservations,
right? Where do you have concentration
camps in India? So, these are all lies,
but it's the justification for a future
regime change operation in India. That's
the deal. Uh Divor Singh says uncle H
can actually be accredited as the father
of our nation more than Gandhi. He
destroyed the UK enough that they could
not stay in India anymore to some extent
you could say. So uh the main thing is
that by the 1940s the UK had extracted
everything of any real value that was
left in India. All the gold, all the
silver, all the minerals, all the value
that could be extracted. India was
totally poorized, beggarized. India's
GDP had dropped to less than 2% of the
world's GDP. When the British started
their job, India's GDP was 30 plus% of
the world's GDP, the the highest GDP in
the world, highest share of the GDP in
the world. So they took everything of
value out of India. They extracted every
last drop of blood out of India. By the
by the 1940s, India's um life expectancy
was 3132.
India had nothing to contribute to the
world anymore. GDP is less than 2% of
the world's GDP. So eventually they they
decided that it's not worth staying in
India any anymore. There's nothing more
that we can extract out out of this
country. We'll have to spend more money
supporting the country now than than the
kind of value that we can extract out of
India. So that's why let's just leave
the country. So to some extent uncle H
contributed to what happened to the but
more than that I think it's the fact
that there was nothing more left left to
extract out of India.
Rahul says is India being encircled
because after Brazil and South Africa is
India is the easiest to contain in
bricks how can we blunt America's soft
power this has nothing to do with bricks
it's only to do with India itself it's
not because bricks is a big deal or
whatever it's because see right now
there are five sovereign nations in the
world the US Russia China India and
Israel Israel is America's number one
ally
so the US will never do anything against
Israel. So then the US is left with
three nations. India, Russia, China.
And Russia and China are are tougher
nuts to crack. Russia is very powerful
militarily, right? Russia can destroy
the entire world with their nuclear
arsenal. That's how powerful they are.
So Russia you can't touch. Ukraine has
been a disaster for the US. They hope
that Ukraine would destroy Russia. It's
been the opposite, right? Russia has
become more powerful. China
technological power and very big
military the biggest navy in the world
and uh once again you the the Americans
don't want a war with China so then
who's left it's India so let's break
India first then we'll deal with these
two after we dealt with India that's the
deal so it's nothing to do with breaks
it's to do with India only Jay Tiwari
says Trump tariffs US debt inflation
high is US in decline powers versus
India post Modi who leads India to devel
how many questions do you Sir, future
outbreaks in it. Let's let's
we'll take one question. I mean
u is the US in decline? Not really. The
US is at its peak at the peak of its
military power and power projection. But
culturally and and as as a society, it's
kind of in decline. Yes. Who could lead
Modi after post Modi? How do I know? We
have some good leaders. Um the
opposition has a great leader who they
wish will come to power and and in the
BJP we have some leaders multiple
leaders who could potentially
uh you know lead the country potentially
after Mr. Modi whenever Mr. Modi decides
to step down whenever it happens in the
future. So you have you can think of
several leaders in the BJP like Mr. Dind
like Yogi Yogiat like Himantab Bishwa
Sharma and I can think of three right
now. I I may have missed some some of
your favorite leaders in in not sure but
yeah who knows it's too early to tell
right now. Future of bricks in its
currency I don't know right now. So
right now there's no there's no talk of
a bricks currency. We'll see if it
happens in the future. Okay. Pawan says
okay no nothing questions. Well anyway
thank you sir. Thank you. Thank you Mr.
Pawan. Thank you. Uh Dimnor Singh says
why when is the face on rupee going to
change? I want to see Ashok Raja Sudas
Priti Raj even though he lost Rajar
Ranjit Singh G even though that they
took his son away indeed I would like to
see some genuine leaders who served the
country and its people I completely echo
your sentiment sir I don't know when the
face on the rupee is going to change I
think it'll be changed when India is
finally free of colonialism
yeah it would be great to see the
leaders you're mentioning on on the
rupee coin indeed or the rupee note that
will that will be the India is genuinely
liberated from from the vestigages of
colon colonialism. India is still deeply
colonized, mentally colonized still even
today and Indians don't even realize
that. So yeah, what you're pointing out
is is is a sign of that that that
enduring colonization.
Jal says, do you think the deep state
wants to demolish the liberals
considering the kind of war Trump has
waged against them? No, the liberals are
also part of the deep state.
They all see the deep state controls
both sides. Why will they demolish one
side? Why? This is all make believe.
This left versus right thing. Liberals
versus conservatives. It's all make
believe. It's all a show that they put
on for your entertainment.
No one's going to de demolish anything.
Joy says, "Huge fan. Love your content.
Keep it up." Well, thank you so much,
sir. I really appreciate that. Thank you
for being a member for 3 months. Thank
you so much.
AVM says why the sudden and
disproportionate focus on encircling
India and not China if the strategy is
G2 then why not let let the latter worry
about India's rise
because if you leave India alone then
the then then the then the world won't
remain G2 it will become G3 in 20 years
they don't want a G3 in 20 years if you
allow India to keep on growing its
economy at 76 6.5% per year for 20 years
then in 20 years India becomes a
different kind of beast
and you don't want that then you can't
have G2 it will be G3 at least so you
don't want problems in the future if you
are a mature responsible nation if you
are a mature mature responsible empire
you don't focus only on today you focus
on what could happen in 20 30 years time
you know take actions right now that's
the reason why they are focusing on
India it is not sudden and
disproportionate it is from their
perspective the right time to do the
right thing.
Divor Singh says most nationalist people
in India are at a at a point in time
where the doits of Chumbell after
independence am I right? I am not sure
about that. The doits of Chumbell
uh that's like 1960s7s 80s and they had
a kind of an independent kingdom of
their own. Were they the most
nationalist people in India at that
point in time? I I'm not sure of that. I
have I've not really looked into that
part of our history. Who are the DOIs?
The only one I can name is Fulen Dvi who
became a politician who was gunned down
tragically eventually. Uh beyond that
I'm not aware of the history. Sorry sir.
And Dn Singh again says was the first
independence fighter Baba Hanuman Singh
Nihang or Mangal Pande?
I think I don't know where the where the
independence fight starts.
We've had a fight for independence going
on for 11 1200 years. We've had
see the first invasion
attempted invasion of India was in the
700s which is uh Muhammad Ibin Kasim.
Raja Dahir fought him if I recall
correctly and he was the first
independence fighter and then you had so
many
kingdoms, kings, queens who fought the
Turks
eventually fought the Europeans, the
British, the Portuguese, the French, the
spa, not the Spanish, the Spanish never
came to India and so on. So I'm not sure
I'm I'm you know there were millions of
independence fighters who laid their
lives down and we will never remember
that. Where's the monument to these
people? There has to be at least some
monument to to the un to the to the
unknown, unnamed, nameless freedom
fighter who died.
Millions of them died fighting for for
the freedom that we enjoy today.
So I am sure there were people who laid
their lives down for us who came before
Baba Hanuman Singh Dihung or Mangal
Pande.
uh not to take anything away from Baba
Hanuman Singh Nihang or Mangal Pand and
whoever else but we only focus on a few
names don't we we only focus on a few
names and I don't want to take those
names right now but the point is that
there are millions who were killed in
the aftermath of 1857
in the 10 years after 1857 the British
hanged 10 million Indians from trees
right who's going to remember them.
Mangal Pande is the is the spark that
set of off 1857, but there were people
before that also. So yeah, I don't know
who's the first independence fighter.
They were all equally important. All of
them laid their lives down. A life is a
life, man. Come on. So yeah, I can't
really name any one person as the as the
spark who set everything off. Yeah.
Spade says the south Saudi Arabia
Pakistan pact raises the question of
who's primary who it's primarily aimed
aimed at India or Israel with the US
traditionally their security guaranter
stepping back who says they're stepping
back
so this is what people are being told to
believe that the US is no longer able to
provide security for Saudi Arabia which
is what Saudi Arabia is going to
Pakistan for security that is what they
you what is that's what they want you to
leave. What they don't want you to
understand is that the US has engineered
this pact.
The objective is to route
military equipment and funding into
Pakistan through Saudi Arabia. That's
all. Okay? There's no other
recalibration or anything.
DN Singh says, why don't we have our own
second amendment gun laws? We need
weapons in case there's a tyrannical
government. Before 1857,
all Indians could carry weapons. And
sometime after 1857, the British brought
in this arms act or whatever which
prohibited Indians from carrying
weapons.
All warrior
class people or even merchants or
whoever they were free to carry
everybody, every Indian was free to
carry weapons for self-defense.
And today because of a law the British
passed, Indians don't have the right to
carry weapons. I think it is an
abomination.
I think Indians should have the same
rights that that they had before the
British occupation. Why do we still have
laws that were passed during the British
occupation that govern India? So maybe I
don't know about guns.
Uh well, when it comes to guns, guns,
they they are a force multiplier, aren't
they? I don't know.
I mean some Indians are allowed to carry
weapons. For example, the Sikh people,
they they have the right to carry
weapons. Even the people of Korg for
example, they have the right to carry
guns and and and swords and stuff. So if
some Indians are given the privilege,
why not the rest of the Indians? Let
everybody carry weapons, I would say.
Maybe don't allow them to carry guns,
not no firearms, maybe your traditional
weapons. I don't know. It's a
complicated thing. It's a complicated
thing. Maybe it'll create more problems
in India. Maybe it'll cause less
problems. I don't know. Uh maybe the the
disarmed people will will finally have
something to defend themselves with in
some situations. Overall, I think that
historically for thousands of years, we
had the right to carry weapons. I think
that right should be restored.
But then it will uh it will change
political equations and what and much
more. So that's why the politicians who
benefit from the way the system is right
now, they would not want things to
change. And that kind of explains a lot
of things. Okay. AKS Baga says, "Why are
majority Chinese Americans so
anti-China?" Who says that?
Really, there are so many Chinese
Americans who have been arrested for
spying for China.
I'm not sure about this, sir. I'm not
sure about this. And even if some some
of them pretend to be anti-China,
I'm not sure about that. Okay. Okay. Dur
Singh says 250 million Americans and
many guns, automatic machine guns, even
flamethrowers and tanks are personally
owned and thousands of rounds of
ammunition per house. I argue the US
public will defeat the army. It is
possible and maybe the army will not
want to fight the population.
Maybe they will stop taking orders if
they are ordered to like do wholesale
warfare against the people of America.
So that's the thing, right? That's the
reason the the US has the second
amendment or whatever it is, the the
right to bear arms and Americans have
all these weapons, really advanced AR
rifles and AKs and whatnot, M16s with
those modified barrel things that that
kind of transform the the weapon into
kind of an automatic weapon. I'm not
sure if it's been outlawed after the Las
Vegas thing or not, but yes. Um the
point is that Americans have a
tremendous amount of weaponry,
firepower, ammunition and let's say
there is there is a conflict between the
people and the government for example
hypothetically and the government orders
the the police and the army for example
to fight the people. Will the police and
the army fight the people? It's your own
people, right? That's also is a
question. So yeah, hypotheticals and
speculations but interesting thought
experiments. Um, and even if the army
does fight, it's possible the if you're
fighting a urban war and rural rural
wars and whatnot, the American public
potentially could defeat the army and
then there would be a new American
revolution possibly.
Divor Singh has this big doubt which I
saw last time also that Anglo-Saxons are
the actual rulers. Who knows who the
actual rulers are? You never know who
who it could be, sir.
Okay. Is it a coincidence that the state
with the most Jews is the most
antinational state?
Now, I'm not aware of this. Which state
has the most Jews?
You're talking about the US, I'm sure.
Which American state has the most Jews
and is it the most? I I don't know.
I don't know about this. Abilov
Kulkarnney says thoughts on big dev deep
but big developed but but irrelevant
nations in GP
what's GP
big developed but irrelevant nations in
GP what is a GP
I know United Nations what is a GP sorry
sir I don't get it I maybe I'm not
intelligent enough says do you think
Pakistani nukes been shifted to the US
or Saudi Arabia. Who knows? I believe
without evidence, I don't have the
evidence to back what I'm saying. But I
believe that the Pakistani nuclear
weapons are actually American nuclear
warheads on loan to Pakistan. I don't
think the Pakistani scientists were
capable of building of developing
nuclear weapons. I think those Pakistani
nukes are actually American nukes. Now,
is it possible they have been moved to
the US or Saudi Arabia? Who knows? you
have we have seen um American um
military aircraft transport aircraft
coming to Pakistan on a few occasions.
Uh it's been noticed in the past few
weeks.
So why do you need to send gigantic
transport aircraft and they said that
they they send the transport aircraft to
to uh to move some uh to to to deliver
some relief materials to Pakistan or
whatever. But they won't go possibly
potentially go back empty. They may take
something back with them. Who knows? So
maybe So do I think this has happened? I
don't know. I have no idea. Is it
possible? It's possible. Maybe some of
them may may have been moved to the to
the Saudi Arabian uh territory or
something. Maybe back to the US. I have
no idea. It is certainly possible, but I
don't know about it. Bangu. Sig says,
"Can India ever match Israel's global
leverage?" Uh not anytime soon. Israel
has global leverage because the US is
Israel's number one supporter for us to
match Israel's global leverage we would
need America to become to become our
number one supporter which is not going
to happen anytime soon so right now not
possible not anytime soon daily dose of
gaming is saying saying your take on
literally upcoming higher act on likely
upcoming higher act US what on earth is
let's find out higher act US what is
this h i r the ACTUS
um higher act 25% outsourcing tax impact
expire Kotak securities I don't know
what this is I've not seen what a 25%
outsourcing tax could mean for Indian IT
stocks a sweeping new bill that could
shake up blah blah blah hire act what
does it do seeks to impose a 25% tax on
payments made to foreign firms for
services consumed in the US these
outsourcing payments covering fees
royalties service charges would also
lose a tax deductibility and so on. Go
away.
Okay. So that could certainly affect
India. It could certainly affect India's
IT exports because India is the primary
IT services export exporter to the US
and it would make Indian IT services
less uh attractive and and and uh
yeah so it could certainly impact Indian
IT exposure to the US. So overall, it's
about cutting off the American
dependence on India's exports. They're
trying to completely delink India and
the US.
So yes, it will certainly potentially
affect India's GDP and and much more
potentially. Godliness says we can't
take on the US as we as a state have
limited resources and 1.4 billion people
to feed. Hypothetically, if you are the
NSA, what suggestions would you give to
the PM to navigate the situation? If I'm
the national security adviser, I would
suggest that make Yeah, we uh we can't
take on the US. No question. We have to
keep our heads down. Don't be
aggressive.
Don't make big statements.
Keep your goddamn mouth shuts. Mouths
shut.
Keep a low profile.
Don't Don't make provocative statements
everywhere. Don't respond and retaliate
to American provocations or any
provocations.
ramp up the military expenditure to 5%
of the GDP. Right now it's less than 2%
I'm sure. Ramp it up to 5% or for the
next 20 years.
Develop Indian jet engines. Develop all
kinds you know acquire at least 50
submarines including nuclear submarines.
Uh create a navy over the next 20 years
that has genuine distributed lethality.
A numerically strong navy. maybe 300 400
warships of different kinds. Um
ramp up the number of aircraft we have,
fighter planes. For that we need
indigenous jet engines or jet engines we
produce in India.
So all of these things need to be done
and we really have to arm ourselves with
the teeth while developing the Indian
economy. So to develop the Indian
economy, we have to become a
manufacturing based economy. uh and
maybe we can become an internally
consumption-driven economy based on the
kind of tax reforms we're doing and so
on. So a lot needs to be done and that's
what I would suggest. I think we need to
ramp up our our defense expenditure to
about 5% of the GDP for the next 20
years. That is that is I think very
important. Keeping it at less than 2.5%
is going to be not good at all. And we
need to become a leader in the space
sector which is going to be an
investment that will be really really
going to it's going to really pay off
dividends
in the future. Not right now. Right now
it will look to most people like a waste
of money but by the 2040s it's going to
be something that will be really
valuable. So that's another thing I
would do. Okay. Abida Singh says can you
do a book signing session when you have
the JPO dialogue summit or justly most
of us would love it. Well, I can do it
when I have physical books. Right now, I
am serializing the book in the
electronic form, right? The black holes
book. Once all the chapters are done and
the entire book is compiled together
with all the resources, all the
references, with all the editing done,
then I will have it published,
which will happen next year. Right now,
I don't have physical copies. So, at
this Japo dialogue summit, it won't be
possible. Next year, next year's Jeep
dialogue summit. Oh, I will have some
books to um do a book signing s session
or whatever. So when the books come out
in the physical form, I will do it. See,
books take time to produce. You can do
these live streams every day. If if I
want, I can do it. But producing a book
is a timeconsuming, slowmoving affair. I
can't bring out books at breakneck speed
like one book in a week. No, a book will
take minimum four to 6 months to pro to
produce
because you have to do it properly. You
have to do good do a good job. You can
make mistakes while speaking. You can't
leave mistakes in books. So that is a
different story. You see books take
time. But whenever the books are done
and lots of books are going to come out
from me. I've got
20 30 40 books in me. All of those will
come out. So you will have lots of book
signing sessions and I I'll I look
forward to meeting all of you in these.
Right. So anyway, thank you for the
suggestion, sir. Thank you. Godliness
says, "Being an Indian, this is the
second time I'm nominating you for the
PUDAM awards." When you when you get
one, please don't forget me. I have
first nominated you. Thank you so much.
I'm not sure if I deserve Padma award,
but thank you so much. I'm I'm really
grateful and I'm really humbled that you
have chosen to nominate me for that.
Thank you so much and I won't forget you
if I ever won win a PUDMA award. Thank
you so much, sir. Godliness, I'll
remember. Dur Singh says, "Amazing
session today." Thank you so much sir.
You're very kind sir and it's always fun
to to field your questions sir. Thank
you. Uh DN Singh says does tradition do
traditional gender roles help the
society? They do.
They do. Call me old-fashioned
called me traditionalist called me
whatever conservative
traditions exist for a reason. So I
would say traditional gender roles help
society. They maintain society the way
it is. Not just the way it is, they
ensure stability in society. Societal
institutions
exist for a reason. Do you want strife
in society? Do you want people wandering
around like headless chickens? Do you
want people fighting each other for for
no reason whatsoever? For no good reason
whatsoever?
Why why do various institutions uh and
and and traditions exist in society? Why
does the institution of marriage exist?
All of these institutions exist for a
reason because we've our societies have
evolved over tens of thousands of years
and certain things have made societies
more stable than other things and today
those things may look like superstitions
but the moment you break those things
you will understand the consequences. I
would say that the the traditional
gender roles, traditional institutions
like marriage, traditional institutions
like extended families etc. they are
very important in stabilizing society
and in forming the the the the basis the
bulv war the foundation of of a true
civilization. So I think it's very
important
says should there be equality of
opportunity or equality of result only
of results. I I firmly believe that you
should have equality of opportunity and
you can never guarantee equality of
results. If you try to do that, you are
handicapping your society permanently.
You should have equality of
opportunities. You can never guarantee
equality of equality of reserve results.
There is no equality of people. No two
people are equal. They all have all no
two people have the same attributes. So
you can never guarantee
if you have meritocracy if your societ
so society is a meritocratic society you
can never guarantee equality of results.
If you want to guarantee equality of
results you have to do do that through
through artificial means like
reservations and whatnot which
demoralizes society. So there should be
equality of opportunity not equality of
results. You can have a safety net of
some kind because some people may not be
able to well survive on their own for
example. Well keep a safety net for
people such people but you can't
guarantee equality of results
says do you feel appropriately
appreciated for all the knowledge you
give out I think I am tremendously
appreciated there are people who who
choose to come and and watch these live
streams uh there are people who choose
to come and ask me questions what more
appreciation can I ask for it's a
privilege if one person chooses to spend
even 2 minutes of the time listening to
what you have to say and I've got like 2
something people watching right now. I
am tremendously appreciated and I can
ask for nothing else. I think I'm I'm a
very privileged person and I never take
this for granted. I am very very
grateful that people actually spend the
time to listen to what I have to say. I
I think I'm blessed. I think I am I'm
amazingly appreciated and I thank all my
viewers for that. Thank you so much.
Ramsh Kalem says uh why and how did you
did US fail? didn't foresee prevent
China from growing to its current size,
strength and like how they are trying to
do with India now assessment failure.
I think the US was overconfident.
I think Nixon and Kissinger believed
that if we bring China, if we integrate
China into our westernled economic
order, then China as they grow more
prosperous, they will naturally become a
more democratic nation. that by the time
China is a reasonably pro prosperous
society, they'll be a democracy just
like us and we'll be able to democratize
China. That was their belief and they
were so misguided in that.
So their assessment was entirely
incorrect. China reverted to its old
imperial system. They became even more
imperialistic over time as they as they
became uh as as their economy grew. And
by 2008 or something the Americans
realized they had made a major mistake.
And by 2012 Chinese China's behavior
changed entirely. You know that that
wolf warrior behavior and all that which
which went on for about close to a
decade. So it was a major assessment
failure. The Americans aided and abetted
and midwifed the rise of their major
rival today. Huge huge mistake and they
won't repeat that mistake with India.
Pratam says can you explain the nature
of power in more detail I have to write
a book for that you can't explain the
nature of power basic nature of power
okay political power like Maungum said
flows out of the barrel of a gun which
means that whoever has the capacity to
unleash violence is powerful and the
amount of powerful the amount of power
you have is directly proportional to the
amount of violence you can unleash on
demand
you don't have to unleash the violence
you need to have the capacity to unleash
it. That's political power. Let's say I
have 3,000 gundas at my disposal.
I don't unleash them on the people, but
I have them. That's power. You see, what
if I had instead of 3,3 lakh gundas,
imagine that. Imagine I have 1 million
highly trained
soldiers who are armed to their teeth.
Imagine the power that comes with that.
Yeah, I may not I may choose to not use
that but see so that's the nature of
power at the basis at the root of power
is raw naked violence or the capacity to
unleash this violence you may choose not
to unleash it but you should have the
capacity that's that's power
says which missiles did Israel use to
attack Qatar I have no idea sorry sir I
I did not look into it um I believe they
used F-35s or something and some some
missiles launched from there I suppose
but I don't know which missiles sorry so
sorry I can't answer that question we
can we can Google it I'm not sure it's
if it's known to the media which
missiles used so
cinnamon no question but thank you so
much I really appreciate your your
contribution thank you very much sir or
manual
says will Russia Ukraine war spark a
wider Europe war it all depends on the
on the actions of the combatants
does NATO seek to widen the war. Does
Putin seek to conquer more European
countries? These are the questions that
will answer whether the this war can
spark a wider Ukraine war Europe war. I
don't believe for one second or
microscond that Putin has has any dreams
of conquering other European countries.
So from Russia's side, I don't think
there's going to be escalation into
other European countries. But does NATO
want to escalate the war to let's say
Poland or to the Baltic countries or
something? If they take actions that
that have this kind of consequence then
there could be a wider European war. So
it depends on the actions of NATO as
well as Russia. Gali versus you cannot
say such things. I cannot read that out
aloud.
U so
those words were expuned from the German
national anthem, weren't they? So how
can the uber folk the uber folk
reconcile with mers and tail waggers?
So Deutsland blah blah and Deutsch blah
blah blah. So how can the uber folk the
the upper folk the the the master race
reconcile with Mertz and tail waggers?
I'm not sure what Mertz is and tail
waggers is.
What you asking sir?
I know understand the first two uh I
understand this what that means. I
understand that. I understand the uber
folk. Yes. The the master race which is
what the Germans believed they were. But
what's ms and tailbagers? I'm not
entirely sure about that.
Sorry. Sorry.
Okay. Clause and effect. No question.
But thank you very much. Very kind of
you sir ma'am. And now there's a
question. How do we go about building a
strong identity and decolonize our minds
without losing our inherent values of
inclusion and tolerance?
Inclusion and tolerance. Inclusion.
Look, inclusion is a very dangerous
word. You want to include barbarians.
You want to include any riffraff who
comes into the country. Do do we want to
include the the 100 million Bangladeshes
who are currently squatting on our
territory? Do we want to include the
cookies who have been pushed into India
the past few few decades in the past few
years or god knows how many lakhs. Do we
want to in be inclusive towards
antinational forces? Do we want to be
inclusive towards anti-vilizational
forces? We have to be very clear about
what we mean by inclusivity.
What do we mean by tolerance? We have we
are not a tolerant society. We are a
respectful society. There's a massive
difference between tolerance and
respect. Shall I tolerate you at my
dinner table? I mean, I tolerate dogs
sometimes at my dinner table. If I am an
English lord,
English lords tolerated dogs and cats at
their dinner table. So, shall I, if you
come to my house as a guest, shall I
tolerate you like that at my dinner
table? That is such a disrespectful
term, tolerance.
You either respect or don't respect.
Don't tolerate.
Sometimes you have to tolerate bugs in
your house if you don't have the spray.
Tolerance is such a such a disrespectful
word. Indian culture has never been
tolerant. It's been respectful of those
who deserve respect, not of those who
don't deserve respect. It's not been
inclusive. It's been welcoming to to do
to to those who deserve a welcome.
We are not an inclusive culture who we
we we will not be inclusive towards
those who are dharmic and who will be
anti-vilivilizational, anti- our
civilization, anti- our culture. So we
have to be very clear about that
otherwise we go down the wrong alley and
towards our own destruction. So how do
we clarify these things in our mind and
bring build a strong identity and
decolonize our minds? By reforming the
education system
and by teaching children. then next
generations from the very beginning the
very fundamentals of what it means to be
Indian and what it means to be civilized
and what what it means to be a member of
a strong nation a strong civilization.
How to think critically how to
understand the difference between
something that looks appealing like
inclusivity but which is actually very
dangerous potentially
and how to understand that tolerance is
disrespectful as opposed to being
respectful.
So these things these very fundamental
things have to be clarified in the
education system. Education system its
objective should be to to to
contribute to the nation strong
strong and confident young people who
are capable of changing the world in in
a in a good way. That's what we need.
Education system is the key.
Susan Baratwaj says between you and Oshu
my he has a pool. Okay. Result a brain
that runs on sarcasm and random wisdom.
All right sir. I had never imagined that
I would be you. My name will come in the
same breath as Osho. Osho was an
absolute genius. No question about it.
Uh anyway I I think you're giving me a
compliment. So thank you so much sir.
What can I say? I really appreciate it.
Thank you.
Mad says according to this website three
okay according to this website three
world wars world war II will be made to
happen between political zionists and
Islamists it say it seems like a setup
has been made my thoughts I don't know I
don't know what the future is going to
be like I can see the world going in
certain directions I can give a
probabilistic assessment of what is more
likely what is less likely but I don't
believe people who say that they have
seen the future how have you seen
theuture future are you like what
blessed by the gods so I don't know I
don't really um look into these websites
where which like make definitive claims
that this is what's going to happen
if someone says this is likely to happen
because of so and so reasons I'll I'll
be I'll take it seriously um so yeah I
I'm not aware of this website maybe I'll
take a look at it
world war II will be made to happen I
hope there is no world war 3 and
according to me there is no guarantee
there'll be a world war if somebody is
saying that World War II is going to
happen and it's going to happen between
these sides. I'll say, "How on earth are
you making these assessments? How are
you so convinced? Have the gods visited
you in your sleep or something?" Well,
why don't they visit me? Why Why am I
being left out by the gods? Please visit
me too. Tell me also what's going to
happen.
Uh okay. Prasami says, "Do you think
India can prevail this tough time?" Yes.
With the right leadership, with the
right amount of resilience from ordinary
Indians, we will prevail. We will
withstand these tough times the next 20
years. Why not? We have gone through far
worse and we have come out of it with
damage but still alive, still existing.
So we will come through this too. I am
confident.
Phoenix says you are doing great work.
Thank you sir. Globalist forces uh that
suppress civilizations have paid best
efforts in bat to distort history. Also
please look look into Kukas 6. They ran
successful boycott and non-ooperation
movement. Jind very interesting. I'm not
aware of the kuka 6. They ran a
successful boycott and non-ooperation
movement during the independent
struggle. I I suppose I I'll I'll
certainly check it out. Thank you so
much for the recommendation and thank
you so much for your kind words, sir.
Thank you so much. And I agree that
there are these forces that are that
seek to suppress civilization and that
are very active in BAT and who want to
distort our history and keep Indians
mentally colonized and keep Indians
saddled with this inferiority complex
and keep Indians fighting each other and
seeing each other as the enemy instead
of seeing the real enemy. These forces
are very active. So you are right and
thank you so much. Thank you. I will
check out the reference about the Kukas.
I look into it. Thank you sir. YouTube
says many Americans are sympathetic to
Russia and say China is the enemy. Is it
because Russia is white and Christian
while China is not? What's your opinion
on Mir Shimemer?
Uh there are lots of Americans who say
lots of Europeans also who say that
Russia is not a white country. It's an
Asian country. They're not really white.
They're Asians
because look at their eyes. Their eyes
look like Mongols. Some some many of
them. You look at Putin's eyes. His eyes
are smaller. He may have he may be
blonde. He may have blue eyes but his
eyes are smaller. So there are many
Europeans who portray Russia as an
Asiatic country. And there are lots of
Europeans who don't consider the
Russians to be Asian to be Europeans.
They consider Russia to be an eastern
country or empire. So Russia is
considered to be part of the east like
India, China, Asia that sort of thing
for many people. But I suppose many
Americans look at look regard Russia as
a white country also.
Me personally, if you ask me what what
world what part of the world does Russia
belong in, I would say Europe more than
Asia
because the Roose people, the Slavic
people from my perspective as a child, I
used to see them as white people and
they've got blue eyes, blonde hair,
white skin, they're whites from me, from
my perspective, but then I realized that
the Europeans don't quite see it that
way. Anyhow, uh so it could be because
of the the white-kinned Christianity and
all that which is a different form of
Christianity, Orthodox Christianity,
more like the Greek form of
Christianity, right? The Russian form of
Christianity. My opinion on Mir Shmer,
he's a realist. I haven't really studied
him in detail. I haven't really read his
works. I have acquired a couple of his
books, but I haven't had the time to
read those. So, I will reserve my
judgment. I from what I've seen of him,
he is a very realistic person. He's a
realist. He's um not an idealist. is not
someone who
um runs on ideology. He's a more
realistic person. Uh does he have a does
he have a soft corner for for Russia and
China like some people say? I'm not sure
about that. I'll have to read his books
in detail to understand that. So I'm
going to reserve my judgment towards Mir
Shimmer, but from what I see of him, he
is a realist.
Amisha says, "Thank you for your
answers. You're the best." Thank you so
much, man. Thank you so much. Appreciate
that.
Achendi Anandan says I want to how to
start Sham series maths for arts
background. If you are from the arts
background it means that you have not
really focused a lot on mathematics. I
understand. So you start with the very
basic shom series books for example uh
beginning algebra or something which
will also re you know help you review
basic arithmetic. So you don't start
with college algebra or whatever. You
start with a very basic algebra or maybe
even something before algebra. Do they
have basic mathematics in sh series? I'm
not sure. So check it out. They have a
whole show series has so many books. So
you look for the beginner books and then
you progress step by step. You you
revise your basic mathematics.
Then you go into beginner algebra. Then
you go into like geometry or whatever.
Geometric coordinate geometry sort of
you know circles and triangles and quad
quadrilaterals and all that
stuff that I learned a long long time
ago. Then you go into trigonometry and
then you can go into college algebra and
then you can go into basic pre-calculus
and then actual calculus and then
advanced calculus. Then you can go into
differential equations and go into
linear linear algebra. Then if you wish
you can go to tensor calculus if you
wish. I'm going too far ahead. So start
with the very basics. That's what I
would say. But tom is great. You don't
need a teacher if you have to. Uh DN
Singh says a couple of months, a couple
of us made a telegram group your viewers
to communicate with each other. Well, a
couple of us made a telegram group your
viewers to communicate with each other.
Well, I would say that whoever wishes to
join Dor Singh's telegram group should
join it and then you can communicate
with each other in in a way that you
can't do on on platforms such as these.
Well, thank you for letting us know and
I suppose if you have a link somewhere
you can put it up maybe on your user
profile or somewhere and people can join
that. So I'll I'll recommend people that
those who are interested can check it
out. All right, Jim Swiss has no
question but well thank you so much miss
you Jim Swiss in case you are French
speaking from Swiss otherwise uh Schwitz
or Switzer anyhow thank you so much I
appreciate that and with that we have
crossed three hours and I have dealt
with all the the super chat questions
all right I'm going to end it here
pretty lively session okay there's one
more question okay this will be the last
one for
So Jim Swiss says the first world war
was Kurukhatra Mahabharat. Well you see
if you don't look at the world from a
euroentric perspective then the first
world war could potentially be the b
what they call the battle of the 10
kings because it was not one just one
battle. It was an entire geopolitical
sequence of events including multiple
battles and the entire front of the war
moved from central India all the way to
the western fringes of India
northwestern India. So it was a whole
geopolitical campaign of the Barata clan
of the Indians of the Rigidic Indians
against a confederation of more than 10
clans
and that is kind of a world war which
went on for an extended period of time
and of course so so maybe perhaps the
battle of the 10 kings is the first
world war actually and maybe the Kuketra
war could be their second world war
which came much much later much later
Ramayan you could not call a world war
because it was just a yodhya versus
Lanka but Kurukhetra was a war with so
many different combatants
arrayed into coalitions.
So yeah if you if you stop looking at
the world from a euroentric perspective
two major
um
wars come to mind that are really
ancient. One is the b what they call the
battle of the 10 kings which should
actually be called the war of the 10.
It's actually more than 10 kings. It was
King Sudas, the son of Diwodas, against
an entire confederation of more than 10
clans. Imagine the odds that were
stacked up against him. And with the
blessings of Lord Indra and the active
participation of Lord Indra, he was able
to overcome uh the this confederation
and shape Bat the way it eventually came
to be.
So anyway, very interesting thoughts
that you have put forward here and I
agree that Kurukhetra is either the
first actual world war or maybe the
second world war based on a
non-hurocentric perspective. With that
let us end this live stream. Thank you
everybody for watching for participating
for all the questions. really appreciate
that and I shall end this here and I
look forward to to interacting way more
with all of you and taking as many
questions as possible in the next live
streams in in the future live streams.
So thank you so much everyone take care
keep asking questions keep learning keep
raising your standards and do check out
the books do check out my books I'm now
publishing books and eventually the
books will come out in physical form the
latest book is about is about Dr.
Subraman Chandra Shashaka the first ever
astrophysicist to win the Nobel Prize
and the horrific discrimination he went
through and despite that he prevailed.
That's the third book that I've
published in the black hole series.
Check it out. Take care. I'll see you in
the next one. Thank you. Bye-bye.